<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A vindication of Sr. Robert King's designs and actions in relation to the late and present Lord Kingston being an answer to a scandalous libel, lately sent abroad under the title of Materials for a bill of discovery against Sir Robert King, Bar., Anthony Raymond, Charles Gosling, [and others].</title>
            <author>Pullen, Tobias, 1648-1713.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1699</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 172 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 118 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A56273</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing P4196</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R6735</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12379744</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12379744</idno>
            <idno type="VID">60711</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A56273)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 60711)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 223:22)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A vindication of Sr. Robert King's designs and actions in relation to the late and present Lord Kingston being an answer to a scandalous libel, lately sent abroad under the title of Materials for a bill of discovery against Sir Robert King, Bar., Anthony Raymond, Charles Gosling, [and others].</title>
                  <author>Pullen, Tobias, 1648-1713.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>234 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[Dublin :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1699.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Written by Tobias Pullen? Cf. BM.</note>
                  <note>Place of publication from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Kingston, Robert King, --  Baron, d. 1693.</term>
               <term>Materials for a bill of discovery.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-12</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-12</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-01</date>
            <label>Olivia Bottum</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-01</date>
            <label>Olivia Bottum</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:60711:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:60711:1"/>
            <p>
               <hi>A VINDICATION OF S<hi rend="sup">r.</hi>
               </hi> ROBERT KING<hi>'s Deſigns and Actions, In Relation to the late, and preſent LORD</hi> KINGSTON.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>BEING AN ANSWER To a Scandalous Libel, lately ſent abroad under the Title of MATERIALS</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>For a Bill of Diſcovery againſt Sir</hi> Robert King, <hi>Bar.</hi> Anthony Raymond, Charles Goſling, William Sprigge, Anthony Cope, <hi>Dean of</hi> Elphin, Anthony Sheppard, <hi>Mrs.</hi> Choppyne, Thomas Twigge, Garreit Miſſet, <hi>Cap.</hi> Samuel Paſh, <hi>Dean</hi> Francis Quaile, <hi>Lady</hi> Kingston, <hi>Mr.</hi> Rochfort, <hi>Sir—St.</hi> George, Arthur Cooper, James Johnſon, John Reading, William Palmer, Henry Farrell, <hi>and</hi> Standiſh Hartſtrong, <hi>Junior, <abbr>Esq</abbr>.</hi>
            </p>
            <q>
               <hi>Ornari Res ipſa negat, contenta doceri.</hi> 
               <bibl>Horat.</bibl>
            </q>
            <p>
               <hi>Printed in the Year,</hi> 1699.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:60711:2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:60711:2"/>
            <head>A VINDICATION OF S<hi rend="sup">r.</hi> 
               <hi>ROBERT KING</hi>'s Deſigns and Actions, In Relation To the late, and preſent Lord <hi>KINGSTON:</hi> BEING <hi>An Anſwer to a</hi> Scandalous Libel, <hi>lately ſent abroad under the Ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle of</hi> Materials for a Bill of Diſcovery <hi>againſt Sir</hi> Robert King, <hi>Bar<hi rend="sup">net.</hi>
               </hi> Anthony Ray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mond, Charles Goſling, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>WHILST ſome of thoſe whom Sir <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert King</hi> thought he had ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lig'd
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:60711:3"/>
to be his Friends, ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſt their Unkindneſs to him in reproachful <hi>Diſcourſes</hi> only, he judg'd it unneceſſary to return any Formal Anſwer to them in <hi>Writing;</hi> believing his own Reputation ſo well Eſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bliſh'd in the World, as to be a ſufficient Defence againſt the moſt violent Efforts of that nature: But ſeeing thoſe ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vere Reflections that were paſt on him (tho' as unjuſtly rais'd, as induſtriouſly ſpread abroad) are lately form'd into a <hi>Libel,</hi> and publickly appear againſt him under the <hi>Specious</hi> Title of <hi>Materials, for a Bill of Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>covery againſt Sir</hi> Robert King, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> He thought himſelf ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lig'd to vindicate his own
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:60711:3"/>
               <hi>Innocency,</hi> in the ſame manner in which it was aſperſed, by returning a diſtinct Anſwer to each particular Article of his <hi>Accuſation.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And tho' the Author of the <hi>Materials</hi> of that <hi>Bill of Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>covery,</hi> or rather of Indictment, againſt Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> has been very careful in obſerv<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the known Maxim of miſchievous Policy, by <hi>ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plying the want of Truth in the Accuſation, by the Boldneſs and Heinouſneſs of the Charge:</hi> Yet I do not queſtion, but that the Anſwer which is here return'd to that Scandalous Libel, is ſo full and convincing, that it will for ever ſilence the unrea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonable Clamour of Sir <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert</hi>'s
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:60711:4"/>
Adverſaries, and effectu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ally acquit him in the Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of all candid and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>genuous Men.</p>
            <p>The confus'd Materials of this pretended <hi>Bill of Diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very</hi> may be reduc'd to theſe Four Heads. <hi>Firſt,</hi> Thoſe Matters that relate to Sir <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert King's Guardianſhip,</hi> of the late and preſent Lord <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton. Secondly,</hi> The Circum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtances of the <hi>preſent Lord</hi>'s <hi>Marriage. Thirdly,</hi> The <hi>late Lord</hi>'s <hi>Diſinheriting the preſent Lord, and Settling his Eſtate on Sir</hi> Robert King <hi>and his Heirs.</hi> And, <hi>Fourthly,</hi> the <hi>Settlements,</hi> and other <hi>Deeds,</hi> relating to the late and preſent Lord <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton</hi>'s Eſtate.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="7" facs="tcp:60711:4"/>
The Complaints relating to the Firſt Head, are theſe:</p>
            <p>
               <hi>That</hi> John <hi>Lord</hi> Kingſton, <hi>the Father of the late, and preſent Lord, having deſign'd his two Sons to be committed to the Tui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the late Earl of</hi> Arran, <hi>by reaſon their Uncle, Sir</hi> Robert King, <hi>was too near related, and in Remainder, for want of Iſſue, of them, to the Eſtate of</hi> Boyle, <hi>Sir</hi> Robert King, <hi>by his Accom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plices, particularly</hi> Anthony Ray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mond, <hi>perſwaded the late and preſent Lord to chuſe him for their Guardian.—That by Contrivance of the ſaid</hi> Raymond, <hi>Sir</hi> Robert <hi>got all the Patents, Rent-Rolls,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>into his Hands, and pick'd out ſuch Inſtruments out of his Brother's Agents, Stew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ards,</hi>
               <pb n="8" facs="tcp:60711:5"/>
&amp;c. <hi>viz.</hi> Raymond, Goſling, <hi>Captain</hi> Caulfield, <hi>as enabled him to carry on his De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſigns againſt his Nephews. That he Acted ſolely without the Concur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rence of the other Executors.—That Captain</hi> Blackwell, <hi>one of the Lord</hi> John<hi>'s Truſtees, and always an Oppoſer of the Deſigns of Sir</hi> Robert, <hi>was bought off from Acting; That Sir</hi> Robert <hi>never return'd an Inventory of the Goods and Chattels, nor any Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count of his management into the Prerogative Office.—That immediately after the late Lord</hi> John<hi>'s Death, he remov'd the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Lord from</hi> Kilkenny-School, <hi>and for the ſpace of a Year gave his Brother and him the liberty to follow their own Inclinations; which</hi>
               <pb n="9" facs="tcp:60711:5"/>
               <hi>gave the Eldeſt an Opportunity of minding nothing but Hunting, and keeping mean Company: and the Youngeſt of Trifling away his Time very Idly alſo: and that when the late Lord was perſwaded to go abroad, Sir</hi> Robert <hi>would not permit the preſent Lord to Travel into</hi> France <hi>with his Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, tho' earneſtly deſir'd with Tears; nor wou'd ſend him over to him, tho' his Brother writ fre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quently and preſſingly for him, and ſent Captain</hi> Pach <hi>to bring him: That the preſent Lord being placed at</hi> Charlevile-School, <hi>and com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted to</hi> Raymond<hi>'s Care, he was wholly neglected there; his truſty Servant</hi> Roger Brennan, <hi>being turn'd off by Sir</hi> Robert<hi>'s Orders, and a Boy preferr'd to</hi>
               <pb n="10" facs="tcp:60711:6"/>
               <hi>wait on him, who was not capable of ſerving him, nor of ſeeing any ill deſigns that were form'd againſt him; That on Sr.</hi> William King<hi>'s taking notice of, and expreſſing a concern for his ill uſuage there, he was remov'd thence, on a pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tence that Sir</hi> William King <hi>de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſign'd to Marry him to his Daug<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter; That being brought to</hi> Boyle <hi>and one</hi> Lightbourn <hi>appointed to be his Tutor, they both ſpent their whole time in Idleneſs; Sir</hi> Robert King <hi>in the mean while not vouch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſafing to make the leaſt Enquiry concerning his Studies, or any thing that tended to his good, though he lived within three Miles of</hi> Boyle. <hi>That being ſent to the College, he was within ſome few Months after his Admiſſion remov'd to</hi> Abby<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>boyle.
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:60711:6"/>
               <hi>That Sir</hi> Robert <hi>by neg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lecting to disburſe three hundred Pounds for this preſent Lord's uſe, when he and</hi> Raymond <hi>had Fifteen hundred Pounds of his Money in their hands, loſt him Captain</hi> Holcroft<hi>'s Eſtate, which was worth Four Hundred Pounds</hi> per annum: <hi>That Sir</hi> Robert <hi>underhand encouraged his Father in Law Capt.</hi> Choppyne <hi>to buy it, in hopes of his Settling it after his Deceaſe on Sir</hi> Robert <hi>and his Heirs; and in fine, that Sir</hi> Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert King, <hi>to avoid giving an Account of his Truſt, which he had broken in ſundry particulars; ſhifted off the Guardian-ſhip of the preſent Lord, and plac'd it on the late Lord</hi> Robert, <hi>who was then but juſt Twenty one Years of Age.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="12" facs="tcp:60711:7"/>
To all which the following Anſwer is return'd: <hi>Firſt,</hi> That Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> was ſo far from endeavouring to divert <hi>John</hi> Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> from appoint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the late Earl of <hi>Arran</hi> to be Guardian to his Sons, that he never knew or heard of his having form'd any ſuch Deſign; and that after his Death (there being no Guardian nam'd in the Will) moſt of all the Tru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtees, and particularly that very Capt. <hi>Blackwell,</hi> whom the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thor of the Materials repreſents to have been always <hi>an Oppoſer of Sir</hi> Robert<hi>'s deſigns, perſwaded Sir</hi> Robert <hi>to take upon him the Guardianſhip of the late and pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Lord,</hi> not miſtruſting that the choice of ſuch a Perſon
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:60711:7"/>
wou'd (to ſpeak the leaſt) be any way prejudicial to their Affairs.</p>
            <p>For though Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> was not appointed by his Brother to be <hi>Guardian to his Children,</hi> there is no reaſon to Believe that, what is ſuggeſted by the Author of the Materials, was the true Occaſion of it: For his Brother having nomi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nated him in his Will, by the Name of <hi>his Dear Brother,</hi> to be one of his Executors, not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding <hi>the nearneſs of his Relation, and his being in Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mainder to the old Eſtate of Boyle,</hi> he did not, 'tis probable on thoſe accounts, judge him un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>qualified to be Guardian to his Sons, eſpecially if it be conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der'd,
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:60711:8"/>
that <hi>John</hi> Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> was ſo far from entertaining any Jealous thoughts of his Brother, on Account of <hi>the nearneſs of his Relation,</hi> that he often earneſtly intreated him to Travel with the late and preſent Lord, thinking that they wou'd be more ſafe under the care of Sir <hi>Robert,</hi> than of any other perſon: And as Sir <hi>Robert</hi> do's declare, that he never employ'd Mr. <hi>Raymond</hi> to perſwade the late and pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> to accept of him for their Guardian, (the truth of which <hi>Raymond</hi> has de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clar'd upon Oath) <note n="*" place="margin">
                  <hi>Vid.</hi> Ray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mond<hi>'s De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſition in the Appen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dix.</hi> No. 1.</note> So neither were the Circumſtances of Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s Fortune ſo inconſider<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able, nor his Reputation in the
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:60711:8"/>
World ſo bad, that he could reaſonably be ſuſpected to have had any ſelf-intereſted deſign in the management of his Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phews Affairs; but on the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary, Sir <hi>Robert</hi> has good rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon to Believe, that (beſides the fatigue of frequent Winter Journeys from <hi>Conaught</hi> to <hi>Dublin,</hi> for the ſecurity or im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>provement of their Fortunes, his long ſtays there, his trouble in following ſeveral of their Law-Suits, and the neglect of his own Buſineſs to attend theirs) he expended ſeveral hundred Pounds of his own Money, which, tho' laid out for their Advantage, was never placed to their Account, as ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pears by Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s Anſwer
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:60711:9"/>
upon Oath to a Bill in <hi>Chancery</hi> in <hi>Michaelmas Term</hi> 1697. And as the ſole intention of his com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plying with the deſires of his Nephews, as well as of the Truſtees, in accepting the Office of Guardian to them, was to expreſs his Gratitude to his Brother, by his care and good Management of the Perſons and Concerns of his Children, ſo he thought he had diſcharg'd that Truſt with ſo much faith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fulneſs as might, if not merit their acknowledgments, yet at leaſt free him from their Cen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſures. And it is ſufficiently known to the World, what great regard the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> had for him, and with what kindneſs and reſpect he
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:60711:9"/>
always Treated him, which did abundantly teſtifie the due ſenſe his Lordſhip had of his Unckles care in his Education, and of his juſt management of his Eſtate; and muſt needs render the contrary uſuage Sir <hi>Robert</hi> has lately met with from the preſent Lord, the more un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eaſie and ſurprizing to him, he having always had an equal care of the concerns of both the Brothers, and no leſs af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fection for the Younger, than he had for the Elder, which will appear by the further Anſwers to the Materials for the pretended Bill of Diſcove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries againſt him.</p>
            <p>But amongſt all the Libel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lers miſrepreſentations of Sir
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:60711:10"/>
               <hi>Robert</hi>'s Actions, there is none more groundleſs and unreaſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able than what relates to Capt. <hi>Caulfield,</hi> Dean <hi>Cope,</hi> Dr. <hi>Quail,</hi> Mr. <hi>Raymond,</hi> and Mr. <hi>Goſling;</hi> for it can't but appear ſtrange that Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s intimacy with their Fathers faithful Friends, and imploying his moſt know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing and truſty Servants in their buſineſs, (which in the opinion of all indifferent Men, wou'd be accounted a Mark of reſpect that Sir <hi>Robert</hi> paid to their Fathers Memory, and the beſt meaſures he cou'd take for the advancement of their Fortunes, and the ſureſt proof he could give of the uprightneſs of his intentions) ſhou'd be objected to him as a <hi>Contrivance to carry</hi>
               <pb n="19" facs="tcp:60711:10"/>
               <hi>on his own Deſigns againſt them;</hi> for certainly theſe perſons might with much more ſhew of rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, be judg'd <hi>Spies</hi> on Sir <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert</hi>'s Actions, than (what is in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vidiouſly ſuggeſted) <hi>Accomplices</hi> of his ill Deſigns. Among theſe pretended Complotters with Sir <hi>Robert</hi> to Ruin the late and preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> Mr. <hi>Anthony Raymond</hi> is mentio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned as the Chief; who was not only bred up from his Child<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hood under the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Grandfather Sir <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Fenton,</hi> and conſtantly im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ploy'd by him in his buſineſs, but as a Mark of Sir <hi>William</hi>'s more than ordinary regard for him, and his entire Confidence in him, was made a Truſtee in
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:60711:11"/>
ſeveral of his Deeds, and par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticularly in a Deed for the Settlement of part of his E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtate on this preſent Lord <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton.</hi> And the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Father had ſo long Experience and ſo great an Eſteem of the Faithfulneſs of Mr. <hi>Raymond</hi>'s Service, and the Prudence of his Management, that he recommended him to his Truſtees, as the fitteſt Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon to manage the Eſtates of both his Children in <hi>Munſter:</hi> So that it happens very un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>luckily to the Libeller, That this very <hi>Raymond,</hi> who is re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſented by him as a mighty Grievance to the late, and pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> and the Employing of whom is ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jected
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:60711:11"/>
to Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> as a heinous Crime, ſhou'd not on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly be conſtantly employ'd, and much approv'd of by their Father and Grandfather, during their Lives, but alſo Bequeath'd (as I may juſtly ſay) at their Deaths as a con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiderable Legacy to their Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren.</p>
            <p>And to make good that fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vourable Opinion they had of him, and fully to Vindicate Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> in Employing him, he has (beſides the many inſtances that might be given of his ſucceſsful Induſtry in the late Lords affairs) conſiderably Improv'd the preſent Ld. <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton</hi>'s Eſtate: For, whereas it was not worth 400<hi>l. per an.</hi> at
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:60711:12"/>
the time of his Fathers Death, it was rais'd by Mr. <hi>Raymond</hi>'s Prudence and Care, to near 600<hi>l. per an.</hi> The Truth of which may appear by the Rent Rolls taken at his Fathers Death, compar'd with that which was given in to the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> when his Lordſhip took the management of his Eſtate into his own hands.</p>
            <p>And as by what has been ſaid (and is ready to be prov'd) Sir <hi>Robert King</hi>'s imploying Mr. <hi>Raymond</hi> in the concerns of both his Nephews, is abun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dantly juſtify'd, ſo what is ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jected concerning his <hi>Acting without the Concurrence of the other two Executors,</hi> will be fully clear'd, if we conſider that the
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:60711:12"/>
late Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> who was named <hi>Firſt</hi> Executor in his Father's Will, was at the time of his Fathers Death, and for ſome Years after, in his Mino<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity; and on that Account was not ſo properly qualify'd to Act; and that the late Lord Chief Juſtice <hi>Povey,</hi> who was the other Executor, had not leaſure, by reaſon of the Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick Station he was in, to at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend ſuch Affairs; and that tho' by frequent Indiſpoſitions of Body, he was diſabled to un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dergo the Fatigues of long Journeys into <hi>Munſter</hi> and <hi>Conaught,</hi> yet he did give his Advice and Aſſiſtance to Sir <hi>Robert</hi> in the diſcharge of the Executorſhip, and approv'd of
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:60711:13"/>
his management of Affairs as long as he continued in this Kingdom.</p>
            <p>As touching Capt. <hi>Blackwell,</hi> he was a <hi>Creditor</hi> as well as a <hi>Truſtee,</hi> and by his indeavour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to <hi>Impair</hi> rather than <hi>Improve</hi> the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tunes, he became indeed <hi>a con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtant Oppoſer of Sir</hi> Robert<hi>'s de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſigns, viz.</hi> of preſerving the late Lord from being wrong'd by him; for he having claim'd a greater Debt than was really due to him, and Sir <hi>Robert</hi> re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſing to pay it, the Contro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſie was referr'd to Sir <hi>John Temple</hi>'s Determination, who awarded him 1000<hi>l.</hi> inſtead of 1500<hi>l.</hi> that he demanded, as appears by the Award in Mr.
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:60711:13"/>
               <hi>Sprig</hi>'s hands, which as ſoon as he received, he quitted his Charge and went away to <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land.</hi> So that now the Reader may perceive that the Money paid to Capt. <hi>Blackwell,</hi> which is repreſented by the Libeller as a <hi>Bribe,</hi> was the Diſcharge of a <hi>Debt;</hi> and what is ſaid con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning his being <hi>Bought off from acting as a Truſtee,</hi> is to be underſtood of his being cut off 500<hi>l.</hi> of what he demanded as a <hi>Creditor.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Of this and all the other Debts and Credits, Goods and Chattels of <hi>John</hi> Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> Sir <hi>Robert</hi> many Years ago re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turn'd a perfect Inventory and Account into the <hi>Prerogative Court,</hi> and there, if the Libeller
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:60711:14"/>
be pleas'd to make a Search, he may better be Inform'd what reaſon he has <hi>Verily to believe that Sir</hi> Robert <hi>did never make any ſuch return into that Office.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Nor is the Libeller leſs mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtaken in what he ſays concer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s getting into his hands all the <hi>Patents, Deeds, Rent-Rolls, &amp;c.</hi> belonging to <hi>John</hi> Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> for they <hi>never were in Sir</hi> Robert<hi>'s hands,</hi> but were ſtill lodg'd with Mr. <hi>Raymond,</hi> as with a Perſon who knew the matters contain'd in them more perfectly, and cou'd manage them more dexterouſly than any other for the Intereſt of the <hi>Orphans:</hi> Though if Sir <hi>Robert</hi> had kept them in his hands it could not reaſonably
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:60711:14"/>
be imputed to a Guardian, as a Crime to have the Writings relating to his Ward <hi>in his own Cuſtody.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Nor can Sir <hi>Robert</hi> ſuffer in his reputation by thoſe ground<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs reflections that are paſs'd upon him by the Libeller, in reference to the Education of the late and preſent Lord <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton,</hi> there being many Perſons of great Veracity and conſider<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able Character, in this King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom, that can vouch for Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s Care of their Breed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, and Tenderneſs of their Perſons; for it is ſufficiently Notorious, That ſoon after the Death of <hi>John</hi> Lord <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton,</hi> Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> having occaſion to be in <hi>Dublin</hi> for
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:60711:15"/>
ſome time to prove his Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers Will, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> his two Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phews were all the while in the ſame Lodgings with him, Eat at the ſame Table, and after about two Months ſtay, went together with him into the Country, and for the moſt part of that Year were with him in his Houſe at <hi>Rockingham,</hi> where they were Treated with a reſpect ſuitable to their Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity, and with a kindneſs equal to what he ever ſhew'd to his own Children; and were ſo far from being neglected in their Education, or permitted the liberty of following their own Inventions, that Doctor <hi>Quail.</hi> (a Perſon of known worth and Prudence, who had
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:60711:15"/>
been Tutor to the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> in his Fathers Life<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>time, and was much Eſteemed by him) did not only continue in the ſame Station, but had the preſent Lord alſo commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted to his care; and though the late Lord did for a while fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low with too much fondneſs and application, the Divertiſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments of the Country, yet Sir <hi>Robert</hi> was not wanting in his Duty to him, but ſtill imploy'd his whole Intereſt and Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity to reſtrain his too eager Proſecution of them; and within a Year his Lordſhip was prevail'd upon, by his Unkle's Advice, (which was agreeable to his Father's De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſigns) to quit all his Diver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſions
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:60711:16"/>
at Home, to improve himſelf Abroad, being aſſiſted by the Prudence and good Management of Dr. <hi>Quail,</hi> who was appointed by Sir <hi>Robert</hi> to be his Tutor and Compa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nion in his Travels.</p>
            <p>And as the late Lord did not, at the time of his leaving this Kingdom, ſeem deſirous of his Brother's Company a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>broad, ſo notwithſtanding what is ſuggeſted by the Libeller, Sir <hi>Robert</hi> never receiv'd any Letter from his Lordſhip, in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>timating his Deſire of having his Brother ſent over to him into <hi>France,</hi> nor did Sir <hi>Robert</hi> ever know that Captain <hi>Pach</hi> was ſent by the late Lord to bring his Brother thither, but
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:60711:16"/>
to be his Tutor here. It may be true, that the preſent Lord did then, as the Libeller ſays, preſs his Unkle, and perhaps with Tears, to ſend him along with the late Lord <hi>Robert,</hi> but was deny'd; for Sir <hi>Robert</hi> did not judge it conſiſtent with his Gratitude to his Brother's Memory, and the Intereſt of his own Reputation, (being, next to his Nephews, Heir in Remainder of the Eſtate in <hi>Conaught)</hi> to expoſe his Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther's whole Family at once, and in their Nonage too, to the many and great Hazards of Travelling into Foreign Parts; and therefore thought it better to run the Riſque of incurring the Cenſure of Un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kindneſs,
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:60711:17"/>
from ſome indiſcreet Perſons, than too fondly to gratifie the imprudent, tho' earneſt Deſires of a Youth, who, in the <hi>Materials for a Bill of Diſcovery,</hi> is repreſented as being then but Thirteen Years Old; for certainly one of that Age, tho' well fitted for the Advantages of that ſort of Education that is to be had at Schools in his Native Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try, is very little qualified for thoſe Improvements that are to be acquir'd by Travelling into Foreign Kingdoms: and accordingly Sir <hi>Robert,</hi> inſtead of permitting the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> at that time to go for <hi>France,</hi> ſent him to a then celebrated School at <hi>Charleville;</hi>
               <pb n="33" facs="tcp:60711:17"/>
and inſtead of his <hi>Truſty Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vant,</hi> Roger Brennan, as he is call'd in the <hi>Materials,</hi> (who had left the Family before <hi>John</hi> Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Death, and who afterwards declar'd him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf a <hi>Papiſt)</hi> Sir <hi>Robert</hi> ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed an honeſt <hi>Proteſtant</hi> Youth to attend him; and or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dered Mr. <hi>Raymond,</hi> who liv'd near <hi>Charleville,</hi> to have a more than ordinary Care and Inſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction over him: And there being, ſome time after this Lord's going thither, a Report ſpread abroad in thoſe Parts, of Sir <hi>William King</hi>'s deſigning to Marry his Daughter to him, Mr. <hi>Raymond</hi> according to his Duty, gave Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> an Account of what was generally
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:60711:18"/>
diſcours'd: And tho' the Libel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ler intimates that <hi>Raymond</hi> him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf was the Author of that Story, (being, as he alledges, provok'd thereto by Sir <hi>William King</hi>'s kind reception of the preſent Lord at his Houſe, and his reſentment of his Lordſhips ill uſage by <hi>Raymond</hi> at <hi>Char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leville)</hi> yet Sir <hi>Robert</hi> do's not think he has any reaſon to be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve that Mr. <hi>Raymond</hi> did raiſe that report, but that the diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courſe in thoſe parts concern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing that matter, came firſt from others, and is fully ſatisfied that Mr. <hi>Raymond</hi> according to his order, furniſh'd this preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> during his ſtay at <hi>Charleville,</hi> with all neceſſaries and conveniences ſuitable to a
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:60711:18"/>
Gentleman of his Age and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dition, though not with Super<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fluities to gratifie the Extrava<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gancy of his Temper. And Tho' Sir <hi>Robert</hi> do's not queſtion Sir <hi>William King</hi>'s kind concern for, and obliging Treatment of the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> at his Houſe, yet he do's not know of any Liberty he gave him of Courting his Daugh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, much leſs of his deſigns of Marrying her to him: How<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever Sir <hi>Robert</hi> do's acknow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge, that though the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Matching into ſo Worthy a Family, and with a Lady ſo excellently accom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pliſh'd, and of ſo conſiderable a Fortune, was a thing that wou'd have been very accept<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able
<pb n="36" facs="tcp:60711:19"/>
to him; yet, if there had been ſuch a deſign, the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſideration of the great diſpa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity of their Years, and the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>flections that might juſtly be paſt on him on that occaſion, wou'd have made him unwil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling to promote ſo unequal a Marriage; for that Lady who was judg'd no unfit Match for the Father, and was to have been Marry'd to him, if his unexpected Death had not in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terven'd, cou'd not reaſonably be thought a proper Wife for the Son, who was then but 17 Years of Age; and therefore Sir <hi>Robert,</hi> on notice giv'n him of that Report (how ground<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſly ſoever rais'd) thought it Prudent to remove the preſent
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:60711:19"/>
Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> from <hi>Charleville</hi> to <hi>Abby-Boyle,</hi> where he re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>main'd till he was entered into the College at <hi>Dublin,</hi> from whence he was indeed much too ſoon remov'd, not, as is ſug<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>geſted, in order to the giving him opportunity to Proſecute his diſhonourable Amour, but in compliance with his earneſt deſires of going into the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try for the recovery of his Health; and to prevent any loſs of his time there, Sir <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert</hi> laid out for a Tutor for him in the Houſe, and conſul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted the preſent Lord Biſhop of <hi>Waterford</hi> (who had been Tutor to him and his Brother in the College) in the choice of one who recommended Mr. <hi>Light<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>burn</hi>
               <pb n="38" facs="tcp:60711:20"/>
to that Office, under whoſe Tuition he continued at <hi>Abby-Boyle,</hi> near Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s Houſe, plentifully accommodated with all conveniencies without any Charge to him. The Author of the <hi>Materials</hi> is pleaſed to diſcover ſome Secret miſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpendings of my Lord's time with his Tutor, by playing at Cards, and keeping Idle Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany, on purpoſe to caſt a Reproach on his Unkle; Yet as thoſe that knew Mr. <hi>Light<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>burn,</hi> will be apt to judge that he was not ſo blameable as he is repreſented, ſo every Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſidering man knows that this Suggeſtion, tho' true, can be no juſt Reflection on Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s care of his Nephew; for no
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:60711:20"/>
Guardian is accountable for the ſecret irregularities of his Ward, they being of ſuch a Nature, that no care can prevent 'em, no Guardian but a Guardian Angel can always diſcover them, and no Advices nor Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ample, without the Grace of God, can effectually reſtrain them.</p>
            <p>To what is objected by the Libeller concerning the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s loſing Captain <hi>Holcroft</hi>'s Eſtate of 400 <hi>l. per annum,</hi> by Sir <hi>Robert King</hi>'s <hi>neglecting to expend</hi> 300 <hi>l. for ſecuring it, when he and</hi> Ray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mond <hi>had</hi> 1500 <hi>l. of the preſent Lord's Money in their hands, and Captain</hi> Choppine<hi>'s buying that Eſtate by Sir</hi> Robert<hi>'s advice,</hi> Sir
<pb n="40" facs="tcp:60711:21"/>
               <hi>Robert</hi> returns this Anſwer, That he was ſo far from ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſing Cap. <hi>Choppine</hi> to Purchaſe <hi>Holcroft</hi>'s Eſtate, that he never knew of his having any deſigns that way, till he underſtood by Councel that the preſent Lord's Title to that Eſtate was <hi>Null;</hi> and tho' <hi>Holcroft</hi>'s Eſtate might perhaps have been ſometimes worth 400<hi>l. per an.</hi> yet before <hi>Choppine</hi> had any dealings with him, <note n="*" place="margin">
                  <hi>See</hi> Tho. Yeeden<hi>'s Affidavit. Appendix.</hi> No. 19.</note> he had ſold all but 80 <hi>l. per an.</hi> which is the whole that <hi>Choppine</hi> ever Purchas'd from him: And further Sir <hi>Robert</hi> does declare, That neither he nor <hi>Raymond,</hi> as he verily be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieves, had ever ſo much as four hundred Pounds, much leſs 1500<hi>l.</hi> at one time, of the
<pb n="41" facs="tcp:60711:21"/>
preſent Lord's Money in their hands: The charge of his Education, and the Law-Suits, (by which his Eſtate was ſo conſiderably improv'd) toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther with his own Expences, which were very large, uſually Exhauſting the greateſt part of the Yearly Income of his Eſtate, as is plain by <hi>Raymond</hi>'s Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>counts. <note n="*" place="margin">
                  <hi>See alſo Appendix.</hi> No. 21. <hi>An Account ſtated by the preſent Lord</hi> Kingſton.</note> And further ſays, That before the Deeds rela<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting to <hi>Holcroft</hi>'s Eſtate were queſtion'd, Sir <hi>Robert</hi> had giv'n up his Guardianſhip of the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Lord, and transfer'd it to his Brother, and never after<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards Intermedled with his Eſtate.</p>
            <p>As to the only remaining objection relating to Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s
<pb n="42" facs="tcp:60711:22"/>
Guardianſhip of the late and preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> which, in the Libellers Phraſe is, Sir <hi>Robert's ſhifting off the Guardian<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip of the preſent Lord, to avoid giving an Account of his Truſt, which he had broken in ſeveral par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticulars, and placing it upon the late Lord</hi> Robert, <hi>who was then but juſt Twenty one Years of Age.</hi> The Anſwer in the behalf of Sir <hi>Robert</hi> is, That as the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſignation of his Guardianſhip, and delivering it to the late Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> did not in the leaſt exempt him from being Accountable to the preſent Ld, for the former diſcharge of his Truſt; ſo Sir <hi>Robert</hi> having nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther made nor deſign'd the leaſt advantage to himſelf by the
<pb n="43" facs="tcp:60711:22"/>
management of his Nephews Eſtate, he had no reaſon to fear the ſtricteſt <hi>Examination of his Accounts;</hi> but he muſt acknow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge that the ſucceſsfulneſs of his care in the Education of the preſent Lord, made him willing to embrace ſo fit an opportunity of being quit of his Trouble; and he does de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clare, that as the ſole deſign of his taking on him the Guar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dianſhip of this preſent Lord, was the promoting of his good; ſo the end of reſigning it, was the preventing of his Ruin; for being advis'd that the Deeds relating to the preſent Lord's Eſtate were defective, and that the Title to them might pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bably be veſted in the late
<pb n="44" facs="tcp:60711:23"/>
Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> as Heir at law, he was fully perſwaded that the beſt Meaſure he cou'd take for the Security of the preſent Lord's Fortune, was to place him under the care and Tui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of his Brother, being con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fident, that tho' the preſent Lord's misbehaviour might a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bate the late Lords affections to him, yet it cou'd not the Sence of his own Honour; and that he never wou'd have de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>priv'd his <hi>Ward</hi> of that which perhaps he wou'd not have yielded to his <hi>Brother,</hi> but wou'd rather have quitted his legal Title to that Eſtate, than have done any thing miſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>becoming the Character of a Guardian.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="45" facs="tcp:60711:23"/>
And now after all the fore-mention'd ſignal inſtances of Sir <hi>Robert King</hi>'s care of the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Perſon, Education, and Fortune, let e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very indifferent perſon Judge what ground the <hi>Libeller</hi> had for caſting that Scandalous Reflection on Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> in ſaying, <hi>That for the ſpace of five Years that this Lord</hi> Kingſton <hi>remain'd at</hi> Boyle, <hi>under Sir</hi> Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert<hi>'s Eye, and under Mr.</hi> Light<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>burn<hi>'s Care, he never made En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quiry after his Studies, or any thing that tended to his good.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>I Proceed to the <hi>Second Part</hi> of the <hi>Libellers Materials for a Bill againſt Sir</hi> Robert King, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> relating to the Circum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtances
<pb n="46" facs="tcp:60711:24"/>
of <hi>the Preſent Lord</hi> Kingſton<hi>'s Marriage with his Lady.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Author of theſe <hi>Mate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rials,</hi> being ſenſible of the many conſiderable diſadvantages the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> may lie under on account of his having Married an <hi>Iriſh</hi> Woman, a Papiſt, and one of the meaneſt of the Servants in his Brothers Houſe, is pleas'd, according to the forementioned inſtances of his Sincerity, to lay the whole blame of ſo diſgraceful a Miſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fortune on Sir <hi>Robert King</hi>'s connivance at it, and ſecret contrivance and encourage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of it; which he do's in theſe following words, <hi>viz.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>That preſently after Capt.</hi> Pach
<pb n="47" facs="tcp:60711:24"/>
               <hi>receiv'd the preſent Lord into his care, he diſcover'd his Lordſhips affection to the Lady he was after<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards Married to, and acquainted Sir</hi> Robert King <hi>with it, and preſs'd him to ſend the preſent Lord immediately to</hi> France, <hi>or to remove her out of the Family, to prevent his Marriage, or any other conſequences that might attend ſuch affection, which Sir</hi> Robert <hi>wholly ſlighted: That Sir</hi> Robert <hi>cou'd not deny his knowledge of the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Lord's affection to the Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>woman he afterwards Marry'd; for his Lordſhip having bought her a fine Scarlet Petticoat with a large Gold and Silver Lace to it, which was carried by Miſtake to Sir</hi> Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert<hi>'s houſe, Sir</hi> Robert <hi>having view'd it, ſaid, he knew it was his</hi>
               <pb n="48" facs="tcp:60711:25"/>
               <hi>Nephews Preſent to his Miſtreſs, meaning the now Lady</hi> Kingſton, <hi>and ordered it to be ſent to</hi> Boyle, <hi>to the preſent Lord, without taking any further notice. That after the late Lord</hi> Robert <hi>return'd from</hi> France <hi>to</hi> Ireland, <hi>Capt.</hi> Pach <hi>continued to caution the ſaid Sir</hi> Robert, <hi>and the ſaid Lord</hi> Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert, <hi>who was then his Brother's Guardian, to prevent the growing Affection of the preſent Lord to the ſaid Gentlewoman; yet not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding this Caution from Capt.</hi> Pach, <hi>and others, they ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fer'd the preſent Lord and his Lady to live under the ſame Roof, for above Two Years and an half; Capt.</hi> Pach <hi>ſtill preſſing to let him go with his Pupil for</hi> France; <hi>but was deny'd it. That when the</hi>
               <pb n="49" facs="tcp:60711:25"/>
               <hi>late Lord ſent this preſent Lord for</hi> France, <hi>Sir</hi> Robert <hi>knew that this Gentlewoman went with him. That notwithſtanding the continual Information Sir</hi> Robert <hi>had out of</hi> France <hi>from Captain</hi> Pach, <hi>and others, of the Intrigues between the preſent Lord, and the Lady he Married, yet Sir</hi> Robert, <hi>in his Letter to</hi> Raymond, <hi>ſeems to charge the Fault on his Nephew; whereas he might have eaſily pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vented the ſame, had he not been wanting in his Duty as Guardian, and neglected it out of Deſign.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now ſeeing the Libeller thinks fit ſo freely and Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lickly to own the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Misfortune in Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rying a Perſon very much be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low him; the following Anſwer
<pb n="50" facs="tcp:60711:26"/>
may without breach of the Rules of Civility, be return'd to this Unjuſt and Groundleſs Charge.</p>
            <p>Sometime after the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> began his Travels, ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſervations were made, and Diſcourſes rais'd, of a more than ordinary and ſuſpicious familiarity between the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> and an <hi>Iriſh</hi> Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>piſt, a Servant in the Houſe at <hi>Abby-Boyle,</hi> which as ſoon as Sir <hi>Robert</hi> was acquainted with, tho' he was not in the leaſt miſtruſtful of his Nephews be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing ſo mean ſpirited as to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſign to Marry her, yet being Jealous of his Intentions to Debauch her, he not only ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſt a Reſentment ſuitable to
<pb n="51" facs="tcp:60711:26"/>
the Character of a good Man, but alſo took ſuch Meaſures in that Affair, as became the Pru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence of a careful Guardian, by giving order to Mrs. <hi>Horſey</hi> the Houſe-keeper, a Relation to the preſent Lord, immedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ately to turn the <hi>Girl out of the Family,</hi> upon which the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> went to Mrs. <hi>Elenor Sankey,</hi> one that Sir <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert</hi> had a more than ordinary reſpect for, as being a near Relation to his Lady, and then in his Houſe at <hi>Boyle;</hi> and (as ſhe has depoſed upon Oath,) * told her, <hi>with his Eyes full of</hi> 
               <note place="margin">Vid. <hi>Appen. Mad.</hi> San<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>key<hi>'s De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſ.</hi> No. 2.</note> 
               <hi>Tears, that he had a Complaint to make to her,</hi> which he expreſs'd after this manner; <hi>There is a poor innocent Girl in the Caſtle,</hi>
               <pb n="52" facs="tcp:60711:27"/>
               <hi>which was an Underling, and I ſaw her a quiet Creature, and I deſir'd Mrs.</hi> Horſey <hi>to advance her to be my Chamber-Maid, and ſhe did ſo, and immediately Mr.</hi> Goſling <hi>and ſome others ſaid, ſhe and I were too great, but I know the Reaſon why they are ſo Malitious, She is Honeſt, and wou'd not yield to them in any ill thing, and they (like unjuſt People) have told my Unkle, and he is ſo incenſed againſt her, that he has fully reſolved to turn her away, and has warn'd her to be gone; I know you have great In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tereſt with him, and I beg of you to uſe it now, that ſhe may ſtay; And that he and all the World may ſee my Innocency, I will receive the Sacrament to Morrow on it, I wou'd not for any thing have the Girl</hi>
               <pb n="53" facs="tcp:60711:27"/>
               <hi>turn'd off, and loſe her Reputa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion by me; Pray therefore inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cede for her to my Unkle.</hi> Mrs. <hi>Sankey</hi> does further Depoſe, <hi>That on this ſo earneſt an entreaty of the preſent Lord</hi> Kingſton, <hi>ſhe did, to the beſt of her Remem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>brance, ſpeak to Sir</hi> Robert King <hi>in the Girls behalf, but found him ſo angry, and ſo reſolv'd to turn her off, that ſhe wou'd not venture to ſay much to him.</hi> But his Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip being very intent on keep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing that <hi>Iriſh</hi> Girl in the Fami<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, and miſtruſting Mrs. <hi>San<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>key</hi>'s Interceſſion not to be ſo prevailing with his Unkle in this affair as that of Dean <hi>Cope,</hi> the Miniſter of the Pariſh, he immediately made application to him, who has Depoſed,
<pb n="54" facs="tcp:60711:28"/>
               <note n="*" place="margin">Vid. <hi>Dean</hi> Cope<hi>'s Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fid. in the Appendix.</hi> No. 3.</note> That <hi>Sir</hi> Robert King, <hi>having diſcharged that Perſon who is now Lady</hi> Kingſton, <hi>of her Service in the Family, hearing there was too great a familiarity between her and the preſent Lord, his Lordſhip ſpoke to him to Intercede with Sir</hi> Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert <hi>for her continuance in her Service, urging that the only way to prove the Report of her being with Child to be a Lye, was to let her ſtay in the Family, and that wou'd diſprove it; but if ſhe was ſent away, the People at</hi> Boyle <hi>would conclude it true: Upon which the Dean went (as he declares) to Sir</hi> Robert, <hi>and preſs'd him to grant what the now Lord deſir'd;</hi> and after ſome ſerious conſidera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, Sir <hi>Robert</hi> was pleas'd, out of a tender regard to the
<pb n="55" facs="tcp:60711:28"/>
preſent Lord's Reputation, and on the Houſe-keepers promiſe of a greater Watchfulneſs, and undertaking to prevent any ſuch future Familiarities, to permit that Girl to continue in her Service.</p>
            <p>And it further appears by the Depoſition of <hi>Charles Goſling</hi> 
               <abbr>Esq</abbr> 
               <note n="*" place="margin">Vide <hi>Appendix</hi> Charles Goſling<hi>'s Affid.</hi> No. 4</note> that Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> was ſo far from conniving at the more than ordinary <hi>Intimacy, between the preſent Lord and</hi> Margaret Cahan, <hi>the preſent Lady</hi> Kingſton, <hi>that on Mr.</hi> Goſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling<hi>'s acquainting Sir</hi> Robert <hi>with it, he immediately order'd the Houſe-keeper to turn her out of the Family, who accordingly did ſo, and that it was by this Lords Means She was taken in again.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="56" facs="tcp:60711:29"/>
And from that time the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trigues between the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> and her that is now his Lady, were either ſo long interrupted, or ſo ſecretly Manag'd, that Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> heard nothing of their renewal till after the late Lord <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton</hi>'s return from his Travels; and being then acquainted that the former intimacies between them were renew'd, Sir <hi>Robert</hi> prevail'd with the late Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> in order to prevent the bad conſequences of his Brothers Imprudent and Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>honourable fondneſs of this Girl, to promiſe a conſiderable Sum of Money, as a Portion with her, to a Servant in the Houſe, with whom ſhe was
<pb n="57" facs="tcp:60711:29"/>
very intimate, to induce him to Marry her. <note n="*" place="margin">
                  <hi>See alſo</hi> William Team<hi>'s Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fid. Append.</hi> No. 16.</note> The Truth of which laſt Clauſe, is particular<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly confirm'd by the ſaid Mr. <hi>Goſling</hi>'s Depoſition in theſe words, <hi>That Sir</hi> Robert King <hi>being Guardian to the preſent Lord, and having a tender care of him, to prevent any occaſion of Lewdneſs or Debauchery, between him and</hi> Margaret Cahan, <hi>a Servant in the Houſe at</hi> Abby-Boyle, <hi>did endeavour to get one</hi> William Teams, <hi>then Under-Cook in the Houſe to Marry her, offering him as Portion, Thirty Pounds</hi> Ster<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling, <hi>or thereabouts,</hi> to the beſt of this <hi>Deponents</hi> remembrance. And accordingly the Servant, having ſo great a Portion pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſed with her, very thank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully
<pb n="58" facs="tcp:60711:30"/>
accepted the Propoſal, not doubting the Succeſs of his Wooing; but the Girl having far greater things in her Eye, could not by any Means be prevail'd on to accept of him for her Husband.</p>
            <p>About this time, or ſoon after, that Laced Petticoat (which the <hi>Libeller</hi> mentions) was brought to Sir <hi>Robert King</hi>'s Houſe at <hi>Rockingham,</hi> being directed to Capt. <hi>King,</hi> (by which Name both the preſent Lord and Sir <hi>Robert</hi> were then commonly call'd) and Sir <hi>Robert</hi> perceiving the <hi>Miſtake,</hi> ſent it to <hi>Boyle</hi> to the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton;</hi> but was ſo far from ſaying (as the Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beller very groundleſly al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledges) that he knew it to be
<pb n="59" facs="tcp:60711:30"/>
a Preſent from his Nephew to his preſent Lady, that he So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lemnly declares he did not in the leaſt imagin it to be de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſign'd for her, but on the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary, Sr. <hi>Robert</hi> told Mr. <hi>Goſling</hi> that he believ'd it was a pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent from his Nephew to Mrs. <hi>Goſling.</hi> But ſoon after this, <hi>Margaret Cahan</hi> quitted her Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice in the Family, and Sir <hi>Robert</hi> with great Joy receiv'd and believ'd the News of her being gone to live with her Friends in another part of the Kingdom; which, as appear'd afterwards, was given out on purpoſe by this preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s orders to amuſe his Brother and his Uncle, and prevent their Suſpicions of her
<pb n="60" facs="tcp:60711:31"/>
then going with him, (as the Libeller ſays ſhe did) or of her ſpeedy following him to <hi>France.</hi> For after the late Lord's return from his Travels, Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> being deſirous that his Brother alſo ſhou'd have the Advantage of Travelling, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing then of Years capable of it, requeſted the late Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> who was then come to Age, and had taken on him the Guardianſhip of his Brother, to permit him to go abroad, and (notwithſtanding what is ſuggeſted by the Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beller to the contrary) it was not without great Difficulty, and after about a Years Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portunity that his Lorſhip con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſented to it; and accordingly
<pb n="61" facs="tcp:60711:31"/>
he ſent his Brother to <hi>France,</hi> under the Tuition of Captain <hi>Pach:</hi> But ſoon after their Arrival at <hi>Paris,</hi> the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> and Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> to their great Trouble and Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prize, received an account from the Captain, that <hi>Margaret Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>han</hi> was not only come to <hi>Paris,</hi> to the preſent Lord, but alſo that the former Famili<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>arities between 'em, which in <hi>Ireland</hi> had been happily in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terrupted, were there more dan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gerouſly renewed than ever; upon which the late Lord <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton</hi> was ſo highly incenſed a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt his Brother, that then he firſt form'd his Deſign of Diſinheriting him, and of mak<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> his Heir;
<pb n="62" facs="tcp:60711:32"/>
and accordingly the late Lord often ſent to Sir <hi>Robert,</hi> to ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept of the Reverſion of his Eſtate, and to permit a Settle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of it to be made on him and his Heirs; but Sir <hi>Robert</hi> was ſo far from complying with the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Deſires, or from taking any Advantage of the Diſpleaſure the late Lord had conceiv'd againſt his Brother, that he earneſtly entreated, and at length prevail'd with his Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip, to ſend Doctor <hi>Quail</hi> with all ſpeed to <hi>France,</hi> to prevent, if poſſible, the great Miſchief the preſent Lord might bring upon himſelf, and the Diſhonour he might do his Family, by his indiſcreet Fond<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs
<pb n="63" facs="tcp:60711:32"/>
of <hi>Margaret Cahan;</hi> and accordingly the Doctor was diſpatch'd away with Letters, and Advices from them both to this preſent Lord, then in <hi>Paris, to ſignifie their Reſent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, and to diſſwade his Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip from the Thoughts of the preſent Lady</hi> Kingſton; <hi>and ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cordingly the Doctor went with Letters, and Propoſals of a con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiderable Advantage for the preſent Lord</hi> Kingſton, <hi>and with great Promiſes, if he, the preſent Lord</hi> Kingſton, <hi>obeyed; and Threat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nings of being diſinherited if his Lordſhip would not be advis'd: All which the Doctor deliver'd to the preſent Lord</hi> Kingſton; <hi>whoſe Anſwer was to this Effect,</hi> (viz.) <hi>That he the ſaid preſent</hi>
               <pb n="64" facs="tcp:60711:33"/>
               <hi>Lord</hi> Kingſton <hi>had heard of the Doctor's Coming, and his Buſineſs, and that his Lordſhip was very ſorry he had incurr'd his Brother's and Unkle's Diſpleaſure, and to avoid it, his Lordſhip had ſent her (meaning the preſent Lady</hi> Kingſton) <hi>away; and did aſſure the Doctor, with great and ſolemn Aſſeverations, that his Lordſhip would not concern himſelf with her any more;</hi> yet notwithſtanding all theſe ſolemn Profeſſions and Aſſeverations, the Doctor was not only credibly inform'd of the Woman's being ſtill in <hi>Paris,</hi> but within a while he found out her Lodging, and ſurpriz'd her in it; and at his next meeting with the preſent Lord, not only acquainted him
<pb n="65" facs="tcp:60711:33"/>
with the Diſcovery he had made, but alſo aſſur'd him of the fatal conſequences of ſo Diſhonourable an Amour, at which the preſent Lord ſeem'd extreamly concern'd, and with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>all told the Doctor, that his <hi>Paſſion for her was ſo great, that he cou'd not allay it.</hi> Soon after this, the Doctor having brought his Buſineſs to ſo unhappy an Iſſue, return'd to <hi>Ireland,</hi> and gave the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> an account of the whole Affair. <note n="*" place="margin">Vide <hi>Dr.</hi> Quail<hi>'s De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſition in the Append.</hi> No. 5.</note>
            </p>
            <p>And now, ſince by the fore-mention'd Particulars it do's appear, that Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> on the firſt intimation given him, of a more than ordinary Familiarity between the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> and an <hi>Iriſh</hi>
               <pb n="66" facs="tcp:60711:34"/>
Servant Maid in his Brother's Houſe, gave immediate Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders to have her turn'd out of the Family; and when after<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards he permitted her to be received in again, did it purely out of regard to the preſent Lord's Reputation, and in compliance with the Importu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nities of thoſe whom his Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip had imploy'd to inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cede in her behalf, and on the Promiſe the Houſe-keeper (who was his own Relation) made to prevent all dangerous Familiarity between them for the future; and ſince it does alſo appear, that on the ſecond intimation of the Renewal of their Amours, Sir <hi>Robert</hi> en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deavour'd to perſuade a Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vant
<pb n="67" facs="tcp:60711:34"/>
in the Houſe, on Promiſe of a conſiderable Portion, to Marry her: And further, that on Intelligence given by Capt. <hi>Pach,</hi> of her being with the Preſent Lord in <hi>Paris,</hi> he pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vail'd with the late Lord <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton,</hi> to ſend Doctor <hi>Quail</hi> on purpoſe to <hi>France,</hi> to perſuade the preſent Lord to return to <hi>Ireland,</hi> with aſſurance of hav<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing a conſiderable part of the late Lord's Eſtate ſettled on him at preſent, and the reſt in Reverſion after his Deceaſe without Iſſue: Since Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> I ſay, has given ſo many ſignal Inſtances of his Care, to prevent the preſent Lord <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton</hi>'s Marriage with <hi>Margaret Cahan,</hi> every impartial Reader
<pb n="68" facs="tcp:60711:35"/>
may not only perceive how groundleſsly the Libeller ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuſes Sir <hi>Robert</hi> of Conniving at the preſent Lord's Intrigues with that <hi>Iriſh</hi> Servant-Maid, and of deſigning <hi>to gain his own Ends,</hi> by his Nephew's unfor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tunate Marriage; but will alſo be fully convinced, that the moſt careful Guardian, and the moſt affectionate Friend, cou'd not have uſed more hearty En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deavours, nor taken more pru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dent Meaſures to prevent ſo laſting a Diſgrace to a Noble-Man and his Family, than Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> has done.</p>
            <p>And as theſe many Evi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dences already produc'd will be abundantly ſufficient to e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very unprejudic'd Man, to
<pb n="69" facs="tcp:60711:35"/>
vindicate Sir <hi>Robert King</hi>'s Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>putation, in all Circumſtances relating to the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Marriage; ſo I ſhall mention one more, which, if any thing, will convince even the Libeller himſelf of the Falſhood of his Suggeſtions in this Matter: For in his Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip's <hi>Addreſs</hi> 
               <note n="*" place="margin">Vid. <hi>The</hi> Addreſs <hi>in the Append.</hi> No. 6.</note> to the late King <hi>James,</hi> (preſented to Him by his Confeſſor) he was ſo far from Repreſenting his Uncle as a <hi>Conniver</hi> at his Courting his preſent Lady, that he com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plain'd of the <hi>many Hardſhips that he ſuffered on account of Falling in Love with a Native</hi> Iriſh <hi>Woman:</hi> Nay more, in his printed Caſe that was then offer'd to the Conſideration of
<pb n="70" facs="tcp:60711:36"/>
the High Court of Parliament in <hi>England,</hi> tho' he was pleaſed to paſs very ſevere and ill-grounded Reflections on Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> as being <hi>Inſtru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mental in altering the Settlement of his Brother's Eſtate;</hi> yet he did not in the leaſt <hi>accuſe him of Promoting his Marriage with his Brother</hi>'s <hi>Servant-Maid.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And when it was the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Intereſt to Tax his Uncle (who had been his Guardian) before a Proteſtant Parliament, with <hi>Conniving at his growing Affection to a mean</hi> Iriſh <hi>Girl, and a Papiſt,</hi> He had ſo much Honour as to acknow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge <note n="*" place="margin">Vid. <hi>The Caſe in the Appendix,</hi> No. 7.</note> That <hi>both He and his preſent Lady ſuffer'd many Diffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culties and Hardſhips on that Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count,</hi>
               <pb n="71" facs="tcp:60711:36"/>
               <hi>before his Affection to her (which, he ſaid, grew up with his Years) could have produc'd a Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riage.</hi> By which we may per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive, that the Libeller has a far greater <hi>Zeal</hi> for the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Service, than <hi>Knowledge</hi> of his Affairs; or elſe he would have taken care that the <hi>Materials of his Bill in this Kingdom againſt Sir</hi> Robert King ſhould have been more conſiſtent with his Lordſhip's own <hi>Repreſentation of his Caſe to the Parliament of</hi> England.</p>
            <p>AND now I proceed to the Third Head of the <hi>Materials</hi> for the <hi>Bill</hi> againſt Sir <hi>Robert King;</hi> and they are theſe: <hi>That Sir</hi> Robert, <hi>with</hi>
               <pb n="72" facs="tcp:60711:37"/>
               <hi>his Accomplices, prevail'd with the late Lord</hi> Kingſton, <hi>by all the Artifices he could invent, to Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>inherit the preſent Lord, and leave him nothing at all to ſupport the Honour;</hi> which the Libeller endeavours to prove, <hi>Firſt,</hi> by <hi>Goſling</hi>'s <hi>Letter</hi> to <hi>Raymond,</hi> Auguſt 19. 1679. wherein he writes, <hi>That he was commanded to tell him, that the late Lord</hi> Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert <hi>intended the Term following to cut off the Intail of</hi> Michels-town, <hi>and deſir'd him to provide for it, but privately.</hi> From whence it is inferr'd, <hi>That there was an Intail on</hi> Michels-town, <hi>and a Deſign to cut it off, tho' they were afraid to do it pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lickly: That Sir</hi> Robert King <hi>commanded</hi> Goſling <hi>privately to</hi>
               <pb n="73" facs="tcp:60711:37"/>
               <hi>give</hi> Raymond <hi>notice of it, and conſequently, that Sir</hi> Robert <hi>pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jected the Diſheriſon of the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Lord before Marriage, or any colourable Provocation given.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>That ſeveral conſiderable Steps were made by the late Lord</hi> King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton, <hi>and his Lawyers, and Capt.</hi> Choppine, <hi>in</hi> Trinity-Term 1682. <hi>to levy Fines and Reco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veries of the old Eſtate of</hi> Boyle, <hi>in order to Cut off the preſent Lord's Remainder, and to Settle it on Sir</hi> Robert King <hi>and his Children.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>That Sir</hi> Robert <hi>came to Mr.</hi> Sprigg, <hi>in the Year</hi> 1683, <hi>or</hi> 1684, <hi>by the late Lord's preſſing, as he ſaid, to get a Settlement drawn for Excluding the preſent Lord, in caſe he was Married at</hi>
               <pb n="74" facs="tcp:60711:38"/>
               <hi>the time of the Perfection of the ſaid Settlement, but with a Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mainder left to the Children of a ſecond Wife, that he ſhould Marry, with the Conſent of the late Lord, and Sir</hi> Robert King, <hi>or ſuch of his next Relations as ſhould be then living; and on failure of his Iſſue Male by that ſecond Wife, to Sir</hi> Robert King, <hi>and his Eldeſt Son, and his Heirs Males, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out power of Revocation or Alte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration of the Uſes.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>That according to this Settle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment Sir</hi> Robert King <hi>ſent a Paper to the Lady</hi> Wimbaldon, <hi>for the preſent Lord to ſign, and employed Doctor</hi> Quail <hi>to perſuade his Lordſhip to ſignifie his Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent to that Settlement, by ſigning the Paper; which the preſent</hi>
               <pb n="75" facs="tcp:60711:38"/>
               <hi>Lord, as he was adviſed by his Friends and Counſel, refuſed to do: That Sir</hi> Robert<hi>'s Deſign in this was,</hi> Firſt, <hi>To exclude the ſecond Brother, whom he then knew to be Married; and,</hi> Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>condly, <hi>To prevent the Eldeſt Brother's Marriage, by leaving him no Power to alter the Uſes in this Deed.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>That it was morally impoſſible that this ſhould be done by any other but Sir</hi> Robert King, <hi>and his Accomplices; it being very un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>likely that the Lord</hi> Kingſton, <hi>who at that time was Young, Heal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thy, and likely to get Children, and to out-live his Uncle, ſhould of himſelf propoſe ſuch a Settlement of his Eſtate, by which he was only Tenant for Life, and no Power</hi>
               <pb n="76" facs="tcp:60711:39"/>
               <hi>left him to make Jointures, or Proviſion for Younger Children, or Leaſe for Lives, and which hin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred his own Marriage, and ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cluded his Brother.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>That Sir</hi> Robert <hi>left this Deed drawn in Captain</hi> Chop<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pine<hi>'s hands, in order to be per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fected, and then went for</hi> Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>That the preſent Lord</hi> King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton <hi>having got from Dr.</hi> Quail <hi>the Deed of Settlement of the Mannor of</hi> Newcaſtle, <hi>(which was ſettled on him by his Grand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>Father) gave Occaſion to Sir</hi> Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert <hi>and</hi> Raymond <hi>to incenſe the late Lord againſt him, tho' his Lordſhip had no colour of Right to it: That Sir</hi> Robert, <hi>in his</hi> Letter <hi>to</hi> Raymond, <hi>tells</hi>
               <pb n="77" facs="tcp:60711:39"/>
               <hi>him, that ſince</hi> Jack<hi>'s (meaning the preſent Lord</hi> Kingſton's) <hi>Extravagancies were broke out in</hi> France, <hi>his Brother was reſolv'd to ſettle the Eſtate he has from his two Grand-Fathers, ſo that it ſhall not be in his Brother's Power to ſet it from his Poſterity.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>That this Deed being diſlik'd by</hi> Raymond, <hi>was never perfect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed; but another Settlement was made in</hi> Decemb. 1684, <hi>wherein is a Power to ſettle Jointures, Por<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions on Younger Children, and to make Leaſes, with a Power of Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vocation; but it utterly excluded the preſent Lord.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>That Sir</hi> Robert, <hi>to give the better colour to what he had done, ſent his Caſe of Conſcience, drawn after his own way, to</hi> Raymond,
<pb n="78" facs="tcp:60711:40"/>
               <hi>(who was then in</hi> London) <hi>with Inſtructions to gain the Hands of ſuch Divines as he named, to ſign it.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>That the late King having had the preſent Lord's Caſe laid before him, and reported to him, by the Earl of</hi> Rocheſter, <hi>expreſs'd ſo high a Diſpleaſure at the late Lord's ill Uſage of his Brother, that his Lordſhip promiſed to do his Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Right, by leaving Matters as they were intended in the Original Settlement; but was diverted from doing it by the forementioned In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruments.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>That on the late Lord's Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riage, a new Settlement was made by Sir</hi> Robert King<hi>'s Directions, wherein he got himſelf and his Children Nam'd next in Remain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der</hi>
               <pb n="79" facs="tcp:60711:40"/>
               <hi>after the late Lord</hi> Robert<hi>'s, excluding the preſent Lord without Power of Revocation, the ſaid Lord</hi> Robert <hi>having been plyed with Company, at the Tavern, for Eight Days together, and conti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nually incens'd againſt his Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, while the Deed was prepa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring, till 'twas perfected.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>That the late Lord declar'd to his Lady, that he was ſorry he had ſettled the Eſtate on Sir</hi> Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert King; <hi>that if he cou'd, he wou'd Revoke or Alter the Settle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, or get an Act of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment for doing it; as appears by that Lady's Anſwer to a Bill of Sir</hi> Robert<hi>'s, Filed againſt her in</hi> England <hi>in</hi> 1694.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>That the late Lord</hi> Kingſton <hi>made a Declaration, and Deed un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der</hi>
               <pb n="80" facs="tcp:60711:41"/>
               <hi>his Hand and Seal, Revoking the Settlement made in</hi> 1685, <hi>on Sir</hi> Robert King, <hi>and Granting his Eſtate to his Brother, and his Heirs, if they ſhou'd come within the Law, and the Remainder to Sir</hi> Robert King, <hi>which was proved by three Witneſſes.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>That Sir</hi> Robert King <hi>Op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pos'd the preſent Lord's Paſſing his Pardon, and Reverſing his Outlawry; and when his Endea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vours prov'd ineffectual in both, he got an Injunction to Quiet him in the Poſſeſſion of the preſent Lord's Eſtate in</hi> Munſter, <hi>which his Lordſhip had Entred on by his Servants.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>That Sir</hi> Robert <hi>having Inti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation given him by Dean</hi> Cope, <hi>and others, of ſome Papers being</hi>
               <pb n="81" facs="tcp:60711:41"/>
               <hi>left by the late Lord, for his Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, us'd means to ſuppreſs them; but being Unſucceſsful, he rak'd what Witneſſes he cou'd, to prove them Suppoſititious, to bring the preſent Lord into Infamy, and to Ruine him for ever.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>That Sir</hi> Robert <hi>wrought his Ends ſo with the late Lord</hi> King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton, <hi>as to get him to perfect Deeds to him of</hi> 600 l. <hi>or</hi> 800 l. per Annum <hi>of the New Eſtate.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>That from Sir</hi> Robert King<hi>'s Buildings at</hi> Rockingham, <hi>(to Raiſe which he made uſe of the Rents of the preſent Lord</hi> King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton<hi>'s Eſtate, and which are ſo Sumptuous, as not to bear any proportion to his own Fortune) it may well be inferr'd, that he had his Deſigns all along on the</hi>
               <pb n="82" facs="tcp:60711:42" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <hi>Lordſhips of</hi> Boyle <hi>and</hi> Michels<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>town.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>And that becauſe the Deed of</hi> December 1684 <hi>was revokeable, Sir</hi> Robert, <hi>or Captain</hi> Chop<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pine, <hi>to get an abſolute Deed, pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pos'd to buy the Town of</hi> Sligoe <hi>for the late Lord</hi> Kingſton, <hi>and to put</hi> 2000 l. <hi>in his Pocket, provided he would give up the Poſſeſſion of the whole Eſtate to Sir</hi> Robert, <hi>and ſettle it upon him, thinking the Eſtate kept too long from him; which ſhews his con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtant Endeavour to ſhake the Lord</hi> Robert <hi>off, as well as the preſent Lord</hi> Kingſton.</p>
            <p>Now, in Anſwer to all the forementioned Particulars, Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> does declare, <hi>firſt,</hi>
               <pb n="83" facs="tcp:60711:42"/>
That he never knew, or heard, that there was any <hi>Intail of Michelſtown,</hi> much leſs that the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> had any <hi>Deſign of Docking it:</hi> And that he <hi>never gave Mr.</hi> Goſling <hi>Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders to write any ſuch Letter</hi> (as the Libeller mentions) <hi>to Mr.</hi> Raymond.</p>
            <p>Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> does alſo further declare, That tho' he heard of ſeveral <hi>Fines levied by the late Lord</hi> Kingſton in 1682, of particular <hi>Parts of his Eſtate,</hi> for the Security of <hi>Creditors,</hi> yet of none to his, <hi>viz.</hi> Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s <hi>Advantage,</hi> or with <hi>Deſign of Prejudicing the preſent Lord.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And as touching what is alledg'd by the Libeller, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning Sir <hi>Robert King</hi>'s com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing
<pb n="84" facs="tcp:60711:43"/>
to Mr. <hi>Sprigg</hi> in 1683, or 1684, <hi>and of deſiring him to Draw ſuch a Settlement of the late Lord</hi> Kingſton<hi>'s Eſtate as might deprive his Lordſhip of Power to make Jointures, or Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſion for Younger Children, or Leaſes for Lives, or Years,</hi> &amp;c. Sir <hi>Robert</hi> do's ſay, That he never <hi>ſpoke one Word to Mr.</hi> Sprigg <hi>to that intent.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And (as the Libeller him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf acknowledges) Mr. <hi>Ray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mond</hi> (whom he is pleaſed to ſtile Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s chief Accom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plice) did violently exclaim againſt the Unreaſonableneſs of ſuch a <hi>Settlement:</hi> And thoſe very Letters from Mr. <hi>Raymond,</hi> produced by the Libeller, do plainly prove it to have been
<pb n="85" facs="tcp:60711:43"/>
ſolely of Captain <hi>Choppine</hi>'s preparing, and directly con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary to Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s Sentiments, he having oppos'd the Making of any ſuch <hi>Settlement</hi> of the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Eſtate as ſhould be <hi>Irrevokeable;</hi> and having alſo often declar'd, as <hi>Raymond</hi> affirms in his Letter, <note n="*" place="margin">Vid. <hi>Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pend.</hi> No. 8. The Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance of Mr. <hi>Ray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mond</hi>'s <hi>Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter,</hi> as in the <hi>Mate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rials,</hi> &amp;c.</note> dated the <hi>20th</hi> of <hi>May</hi> 1684. <hi>That he thought it very reaſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able that his Lordſhip ſhould have Power to Alter the Uſes, as he ſaw cauſe:</hi> And it was the Unac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceptableneſs of ſuch an <hi>Irre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vokeable Settlement</hi> to Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> (which Mr. <hi>Raymond</hi> very preſſingly urg'd in his Letter to Captain <hi>Choppine)</hi> that pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vailed with the late Lord to alter his <hi>Meaſures,</hi> and put a
<pb n="86" facs="tcp:60711:44"/>
ſtop to his <hi>haſty Deſigns of levy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing a Fine and Recovery upon his Eſtate.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And ſo far was Sir <hi>Robert</hi> from <hi>having left this Deed in Captain</hi> Choppine<hi>'s hands, with Inſtructions to get it perfected, and from going then for</hi> England, on purpoſe that he might not be thought to have a hand in it, that he knew not of any ſuch <hi>Deed being drawn, or di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rected to be prepared,</hi> when he went for <hi>England</hi> in <hi>February</hi> 1683, as he not only ſolemnly <hi>profeſſes,</hi> but is alſo ready to <hi>depoſe</hi> upon Oath.</p>
            <p>And as touching thoſe Clauſes in that <hi>Settlement</hi> that Captain <hi>Choppine</hi> prepared, and the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> made,
<pb n="87" facs="tcp:60711:44"/>
which excluded the preſent Lord and his Iſſue from the Remainder of the ſaid Eſtate; Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> does freely own, that he was then, and ſtill is of Opinion, that they were ſuch as well became the Honour of the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> to inſert, and of the preſent Lord to have conſented to; for (as Sir <hi>Robert</hi> himſelf declares, in his intercepted Letter to Dr. <hi>Quail,</hi> produc'd by the Libel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ler) <hi>the preſent Lord could not ſure be againſt Excluding the Children of</hi> Pegg Cahan; <hi>to whom, if he be not Married, it cannot prejudice him; if he be, he cannot think her Children fit to Inherit</hi> Boyle, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="88" facs="tcp:60711:45"/>
Now, to ſhew how ſuitably to his Uncle's Sentiments the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> expreſſed himſelf concerning this Affair, and how highly he reſented the Injuſtice of his Friends in ſuſpecting him Married to ſo mean a Woman, and how ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riouſly, in all appearance, he declar'd his Abhorrence of ſo diſgraceful a Deſign, I ſhall produce ſome Paſſages out of his Lordſhip's Letter <note n="*" place="margin">Vid. <hi>The preſent Lord</hi> Kingſton<hi>'s Letter in the Append.</hi> No. 9.</note> to Mr. <hi>Goſling,</hi> dated from <hi>Paris May</hi> the 23<hi>d.</hi> (without mentioning the Year) wherein he ſeverely Reprimands his Friends for their unworthy Reflections on his <hi>Veracity and known Wiſdom,</hi> in believing him Guilty of ſuch an <hi>Action</hi> as would ren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der
<pb n="89" facs="tcp:60711:45"/>
him not only a Perſon of great <hi>Imprudence,</hi> but alſo of a <hi>profligate Reputation;</hi> the Wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man whom they ſuppos'd him to have Married, being not only very much <hi>beneath</hi> him, but alſo one whom he had very <hi>ſolemnly diſown'd by Oaths and Imprecations;</hi> for thus he expoſtulates with them on this Occaſion in that Letter; <hi>Would that be the Effect of one who was counted Wiſe, to play the Fool to go Marry a Scullian, tho' he lov'd her never ſo well.</hi> And then complains of the <hi>hard Uſage he had met with from his Friends, that tho' he damn'd himſelf to the Pit of Hell, he muſt never be believ'd; but that</hi> Bridget<hi>'s and</hi> Will<hi>'s Words muſt go before his Oaths:</hi>
               <pb n="90" facs="tcp:60711:46"/>
And threatens Mr. <hi>Goſling,</hi> that <hi>except they ſend him ſome Recom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pence for the Injury they had done him, by their unworthy and dirty Thoughts, he would never forgive them.</hi> By all which we may perceive, as far as Words are expreſſive of Mens Thoughts, that the preſent Lord <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton,</hi> by his Letter to Mr. <hi>Goſling,</hi> did abundantly con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firm the Truth of what Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> writ to Doctor <hi>Quail,</hi> viz. <hi>That his Lordſhip could not think</hi> Pegg Cahan<hi>'s Children fit to Inherit</hi> Boyle.</p>
            <p>But his Lordſhip being ſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſible how little Credit Lovers generally gain to their moſt ſolemn Abjurations of their Miſtreſſes, was pleaſed to make
<pb n="91" facs="tcp:60711:46"/>
uſe of his Wit to ſupport the Reputation of his Veracity; and therefore the more fully to convince his Friends of the Sincerity of his Proteſtations againſt ſo diſhonourable an Amour, and the more effe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctually to divert them from Entertaining any jealous Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prehenſions of him for the future, he thought fit, beſides the forementioned Letter to Mr. <hi>Goſling,</hi> to write one of another ſtrain to Sir <hi>Robert King;</hi> the purport of which was, to acquaint him of <hi>the late Lady</hi> Donegall<hi>'s being then in</hi> Paris; <hi>of his Intimacy with her; of the Marks of Favour he received from her; and of his full Aſſurance of Succeſs, if he ſhould</hi>
               <pb n="92" facs="tcp:60711:47"/>
               <hi>make his Addreſſes to her Lady<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip: he alledg'd the greatneſs of her Eſtate as abundantly compen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſating for the diſparity of their Years, which he did not think ſo conſiderable as might reaſonably make him to deſpair of having Children by her; but withall, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clar'd ſo great a Reſpect for his Uncle, and Deference to his Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment and Advice, that he would not attempt a matter of that Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſequence without his Privity and Conſent.</hi> This Letter and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Papers were by unwar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rantable means got, by the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> out of the hands of Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s Houſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>keeper at <hi>Boyle,</hi> in his Abſence, in the time of the late Trou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles. <note n="*" place="margin">
                  <hi>See Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pend.</hi> N. 14. Nola Mur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phey<hi>'s Affidavit.</hi>
               </note> The Effect of this Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter
<pb n="93" facs="tcp:60711:47"/>
was what the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> wiſht for, and intend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by it; for by this plauſible but deluſive Pretence, all his Friends in this Kingdom were drawn into a firm Perſuaſion of his having no Deſign of Diſparaging his Family, by Marrying that <hi>Iriſh</hi> Servant-Maid, ſince he now ſeem'd with ſome earneſtneſs to deſire, and with impatience to wait for his Uncle's Conſent to his Courting a Lady of conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derable Quality and Fortune: Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> indeed could not approve of this Courtſhip, and therefore out of the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gard he had to his Nephew's Advantage, and the Apprehen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion of the World's juſt Cen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure
<pb n="94" facs="tcp:60711:48"/>
on himſelf, if he ſhould promote ſo unequal a Match, which gave ſo little Proſpect of Children, he did by his Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter to him declare his utter diſlike of his Deſign, and us'd ſeveral Arguments to diſſwade him from it; but in the mean time, he had ſo entire a Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fidence in the Sincerity of his Nephew's profeſs'd Intentions (with his Friends Allowance) to make his Addreſſes to her Ladyſhip, that Sir <hi>Robert</hi> de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clar'd to his Friends, and par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticularly to his Grace the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Lord Primate, (not with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out ſome Tranſport of Joy) that now he was fully convinc'd that <hi>Jack</hi> (for ſo he was us'd familiarly to call the preſent
<pb n="95" facs="tcp:60711:48"/>
Lord <hi>Kingſton) was not Married to</hi> Peggy Cahan.</p>
            <p>Yet notwithſtanding Sir <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert</hi>'s ſtedfaſt Belief of the Truth of his Nephew's Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſſions, he thought it prudent, for the Vindication of his Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour, and for the effectual pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venting of his diſgraceful Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riage, to ſend an Inſtrument to be ſign'd by the preſent Lord, the purport of which was, a ſolemn Declaration of the <hi>Falſeneſs of the Report</hi> of his being <hi>Married to Margaret Cahan,</hi> and of his <hi>free Conſent to his Brother's Excluding him, and his Heirs by her,</hi> in the <hi>Settlement of his Eſtate, in Caſe he were then, or ſhould afterwards be Married to her, &amp;c.</hi> The Words were
<pb n="96" facs="tcp:60711:49"/>
theſe, (as the Libeller him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf ſets them down)</p>
            <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="declaration">
               <body>
                  <p>
                     <hi>The Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port of my being Married to</hi> Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>garet Cahan <hi>is ſo far falſe, that I am willing, and do hereby freely conſent, That my Brother, Lord Baron of</hi> Kingſton, <hi>in making the Settlement of his Eſtate, do exclude Me, Her, and all the Children I ſhall have by her: But as I ſign this to give my Brother and the World Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisfaction that I am not Married to her; ſo I deſire, in Requital, in making the Settlement, I may have ſuch a place in it as the Laws of GOD and Man appoint,</hi> viz. <hi>That I and my Heirs may Inherit next, and immediately after my Brother, and his Heirs:</hi>
                  </p>
                  <closer>
                     <signed>To this I freely Sign,</signed> 
                     <dateline>
                        <hi>as Witneſs my Hand and Seal this—being preſent, &amp;c.</hi>
                     </dateline>
                  </closer>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
            <p>
               <pb n="97" facs="tcp:60711:49"/>
Now, as the Framing and Sending this Inſtrument was ſincerely deſign'd by Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> as an effectual Means to prevent the Diſgrace of his Family; ſo he did not que<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtion but that it would have been both kindly accepted, and freely ſign'd by the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Lord <hi>Kingſton:</hi> For Sir <hi>Robert</hi> being poſſeſs'd with a firm Belief of the Sincerity of his Nephew's Profeſſions, could not imagine that he who had ſo earneſtly deſir'd his <hi>Conſent to his Courting the Lady</hi> Donegall, and in the aforeſaid Letter to Mr. <hi>Goſling,</hi> had ſo grievouſly complain'd of the <hi>unworthy and dirty Thoughts of his Friends, in ſuſpecting him Married to ſo mean</hi>
               <pb n="98" facs="tcp:60711:50"/>
               <hi>a Woman as</hi> Margaret Cahan, would decline ſo Prudent, and ſure an Expedient, of preventing ſuch diſhonourable Sentiments of him for the time to come, much leſs, that he would ever repreſent it as a Grievance to give that under his Hand, by his Uncle's Advice, which he had ſo often and ſo freely Sworn to many others, and had (as he himſelf expreſſes it in that Letter) <hi>Damn'd himſelf to the Pit of Hell,</hi> for the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firmation of its Truth.</p>
            <p>By all which it may appear, with what Juſtice the Libeller Taxes Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> with knowing that the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> was Married, when he ſent him the Inſtrument to
<pb n="99" facs="tcp:60711:50"/>
Sign; ſeeing he had then not only the Word and Honour of a Man of Quality, but alſo the Faith of a Chriſtian, given in the moſt ſolemn manner, to engage him to believe the contrary.</p>
            <p>And that which abundantly vindicates Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> from the Libeller's farther moſt ſcan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dalous Suggeſtions concerning this Inſtrument, is the <hi>Manner</hi> of his Tranſmitting it to the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton:</hi> For if Sir <hi>Robert</hi> had been conſcious of the Unreaſonableneſs of his Nephew's ſigning that Paper, or had intended, as the Libeller inſinuates, <hi>to Wheedle him into a Conſent of his Brother's making a new Settlement, and to the lay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing</hi>
               <pb n="100" facs="tcp:60711:51"/>
               <hi>aſide the old Intails,</hi> (as the Libeller calls them) <hi>in</hi> Mun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter <hi>and</hi> Connaught, <hi>wherein the preſent Lord had Remainders, im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mediately after the Death of his Elder Brother:</hi> If Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> I ſay, had had any ſuch fraudulent and circumventing Deſign, he would not ſurely have ſent the <hi>Inſtrument</hi> inclos'd in a Letter into <hi>England,</hi> to the preſent Lord's Grand-Mother, the Lady <hi>Wimbaldon,</hi> in order to be ſhew'd to, and ſign'd by her Grand-Son: And as the Libeller does freely own, that <hi>this Paper was ſhew'd to the preſent Lord</hi> Kingſton <hi>by his Grand-Mother;</hi> ſo he does not ſo much as pretend, that her Ladyſhip, or any other of his
<pb n="101" facs="tcp:60711:51"/>
               <hi>Engliſh</hi> Relations, or Friends, did either <hi>reflect</hi> on Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> for ſending it, or <hi>thought it improper for his Lordſhip to Sign it:</hi> For tho' he tells us that his Uncle, Sir <hi>Thomas Ber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nardiſton, Fee'd a Lawyer, who was of Opinion, that it was dan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gerous for the preſent Lord to Sign it, whether he was Married or no;</hi> yet Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> having ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver heard of any ſuch Advice being given his Lordſhip, nor ever receiv'd any ſuch Intima<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion from the Lady <hi>Wimbaldon</hi> in her Anſwer to his Letter, has reaſon to believe it to be an Excuſe, purpoſely fram'd by the Libeller, in order to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceal the true Reaſons of the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſal
<pb n="102" facs="tcp:60711:52"/>
to Sign the ſaid Inſtru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment.</p>
            <p>It has indeed been ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>times the Fate of ſome of the Nobility, both in <hi>England</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> by reaſon of the Smal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs of their Eſtates, and for the Support of their Honour, to Marry into Families much inferior to their own; but then the Largeneſs of their Ladies Fortunes had made ſome Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>penſation for the Meanneſs of their Deſcent; and the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teſtants of Quality, even in <hi>Ireland,</hi> have had ſo due a <hi>Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gard</hi> to the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Extraction, and ſo warm a <hi>Zeal</hi> for the Proteſtant Religion, that few can be found that have con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tracted Marriages with any
<pb n="103" facs="tcp:60711:52"/>
               <hi>Iriſh</hi> Papiſts, tho' of the greateſt Families, and Eſtates; but no ſingle inſtance, I believe, can be given of any Proteſtant Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tleman, of Noble Blood, and of <hi>Engliſh</hi> Deſcent, (except the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton)</hi> who, with great Deliberation, and againſt the repeated Advices and earneſt Endeavours of all his Friends and Relations, for ſeveral Years together, <hi>Married an ordinary Servant Maid, and an</hi> Iriſh <hi>Papiſt.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> was the more ſenſibly affected with this Calamity, and more provok'd with his Brother's Diſgracing himſelf, by that ig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>noble Marriage, becauſe the Woman he had made Choice
<pb n="104" facs="tcp:60711:53"/>
of for his Wife, was not only a Papiſt by Profeſſion, and of mean <hi>Iriſh</hi> Parentage, and in a low Station amongſt the Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vants of his own Family; but was alſo one who had neither Charms of Beauty, nor gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tile Behaviour, nor Agreable<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs of Converſation, to engage his Affections; for tho' it may reaſonably be hoped, that the preſent Lady <hi>Kingſton</hi> is a well accompliſh'd Lady, as having, for theſe ſeveral Years paſt, had all the Advantages that the Court of St. <hi>Germains</hi> could afford, for Improving her to a Degree anſwerable to her pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Quality; yet certainly, all thoſe that knew <hi>Margaret Cahan,</hi> when ſhe liv'd a Servant-Maid
<pb n="105" facs="tcp:60711:53"/>
in the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Houſe at <hi>Abby-Boyle,</hi> muſt ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>knowledge that ſhe was then very far from having any Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compliſhments, either of Body or Mind, to recommend her as a Wife to any Gentleman: And therefore, tho' the preſent Lord was ſo far carried away with an unaccountable Paſſion, as to Marry a deſpicable and homely Woman, as ſhe then was; yet it might reaſonably have been expected, that one <hi>who had been counted Wiſe,</hi> ſhou'd have demean'd himſelf to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards his offended Brother, and the reſt of his Relations, with ſo much Modeſty and Reſpect, as might have teſtify'd a deep Concern, not only for
<pb n="106" facs="tcp:60711:54"/>
his own Misfortune, but alſo for the Diſhonour he had done his Family. But, on the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary, he was ſo far from taking ſuch prudent Meaſures, as might poſſibly at laſt have recommended him to his Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther's Favour, that immediately after the late King <hi>Jame</hi>'s Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſion to the Throne, he did not only publickly expoſe his Brother's Honour, and his Un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cle's Juſtice, in a high reflecting <hi>Petition,</hi> which he preferr'd to the King, and in his <hi>Addreſs</hi> to the Houſe of Lords in <hi>England;</hi> but did alſo, within a while after, to the unſpeakable Grief of the late Lord, and all his Relations, openly Renounce the <hi>Proteſtant Religion,</hi> and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clar'd
<pb n="107" facs="tcp:60711:54"/>
himſelf a <hi>Papiſt,</hi> and merited ſo highly of the Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>piſh Party, and became ſo ſpee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dily famous for his bigotted Zeal, that he was advanc'd to the Dignity of being one of the Gentlemen of the <hi>Privy-Chamber</hi> to the late King <hi>James.</hi> All which diſobliging, ſcan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dalous and diſhonourable Actions of the preſent Lord, immoveably fix'd and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firm'd the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> in the former Reſolutions he had taken, of Diſinheriting him, and Settling his Eſtate upon his Uncle, and the Heirs Males of his Body.</p>
            <p>Now, becauſe the Odium of the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pleaſure againſt his Brother, is
<pb n="108" facs="tcp:60711:55"/>
by the Libeller wholly caſt on Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> and the Diſhe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſon of the preſent Lord is ſuppos'd by him (tho' with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out the leaſt ſhew of Proof) to have been firſt fram'd at Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s <hi>Inſtigation,</hi> and brought about by his <hi>Contrivance,</hi> I ſhall, in order to a full Vindication of Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s Innocency in this whole Affair, produce the Teſtimony of ſuch Gentlemen, as, by their perſonal Know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge of all Matters relating to the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Settle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of his Eſtate, are moſt fitly qualify'd to give their Evidence, and, by their eſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bliſht <hi>Reputation for Integrity,</hi> are the moſt <hi>Credible Witneſſes</hi> in what they do atteſt. The
<pb n="109" facs="tcp:60711:55"/>
firſt Perſon that I ſhall men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, is the Reverend Doctor <hi>Francis Quail,</hi> who not only attended the late Lord <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton</hi> in the Capacity of a Tu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tor, for about a Year before his Father's Death, but conti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nued in that Station for many Years after, and accompanied him in his Travels into <hi>France,</hi> and had alſo the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> committed to his Care, for ſome time, by Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> Uncle and Guar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dian to them both. The ſaid Doctor <hi>Quail</hi> does declare, and has depos'd upon Oath, <note n="*" place="margin">Vide <hi>Dr.</hi> Quail<hi>'s Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fidavit in the Append.</hi> No. 10.</note> 
               <hi>That he always obſerv'd in Sir</hi> Robert King <hi>a great Care of, and Affe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction for, the late Lord</hi> Robert, <hi>and preſent Lord</hi> John: <hi>And that</hi>
               <pb n="110" facs="tcp:60711:56"/>
               <hi>the ſaid Sir</hi> Robert, <hi>at the time of ſending the late Lord</hi> King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton <hi>abroad, being preſs'd by ſome Friends, to permit the preſent Lord to accompany his Brother in his Travels, refuſed to conſent thereto, ſaying, It was not fit to expoſe them both together to the Hazard of the Seas, and Foreign Parts.</hi> And does further declare, <hi>That he always obſerv'd a Backward<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs in Sir</hi> Robert King <hi>touch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing ſuch a Settlement in Excluſion of the preſent Lord; and he ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rily believes the ſaid Sir</hi> Robert <hi>never did, either by himſelf, or any other Perſon or Perſons whatſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever, perſuade or ſolicit the ſaid late Lord to make ſuch a Settlement; and that the ſaid Sir</hi> Robert <hi>ſent him to the ſaid late Lord, to ſig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nifie</hi>
               <pb n="111" facs="tcp:60711:56"/>
               <hi>his, the ſaid Sir</hi> Robert<hi>'s diſlike of it, and to diſſuade him the ſaid Lord</hi> Robert <hi>from mak<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing thereof; which Meſſage the Doctor deliver'd to the ſaid late Lord, at which the ſaid late Lord ſeemed to be moved, and ſaid he would proceed in it, or Words to that effect, and that</hi> Peggy Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>han<hi>'s Iſſue ſhould never enjoy his Eſtate.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And to this purpoſe <hi>Charles Goſling,</hi> 
               <abbr>Esq</abbr> (who was ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>time Secretary to the late Lord <hi>Kingſton)</hi> has depos'd, <note n="*" place="margin">Vid. <hi>Mr.</hi> Goſling<hi>'s Depoſition in the Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pend.</hi> No. 4.</note> That <hi>when the News came, of the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Lord</hi> Kingſton<hi>'s being Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried to</hi> Margaret Cahan, <hi>the late Lord was ſo much troubled at it, and ſo much enrag'd at him, that he ſoon after reſolv'd to Levy</hi>
               <pb n="112" facs="tcp:60711:57"/>
               <hi>a Fine, and ſuffer a Recovery of his Eſtate, both in</hi> Connaught <hi>and</hi> Munſter, <hi>and told his Un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cle, Sir</hi> Robert King, <hi>of his Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolution, and that he would ſettle the ſame upon him, and his Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren: And that Sir</hi> Robert <hi>there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon</hi> advis'd him to the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary, telling him, That tho' his Brother had Married ſo far beneath himſelf, and his Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mily, yet ſhe might make a good Wife, <hi>or Words to that effect; upon which the late Lord</hi> Kingſton <hi>ſolemnly profeſs'd and ſwore, That in Caſe Sir</hi> Robert King <hi>would not accept of the Set<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlement, he would ſettle the Eſtate upon his Couſin, Captain</hi> Francis King, <hi>and his Children; which this Deponent,</hi> viz. <hi>Mr.</hi> Goſling,
<pb n="113" facs="tcp:60711:57"/>
               <hi>often heard the ſaid Lord</hi> King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton <hi>declare; and this Deponent does alſo verily believe, that he would ſo have done, in caſe the ſaid Sir</hi> Robert <hi>had not accepted of the ſame.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Nor can the late Lord <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton</hi>'s Diſinheriting his Brother be judg'd an Act of unreaſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able Severity, if, beſides what has been already ſaid, it be but conſidered, that the preſent Lord's private Fortune, left him by his Grand-Father, Sir <hi>William Fenton,</hi> which he then enjoy'd, amounted to 600 <hi>l. per Annum,</hi> which, to any im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>partial Judgment, will paſs for more than a competent Inhe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritance for the Children of ſuch a Mother. And tho' the late
<pb n="114" facs="tcp:60711:58"/>
Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> ſhew'd a juſt Diſpleaſure at his Brother's diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>graceful Marriage, by Diſin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>heriting his Iſſue by the <hi>Iriſh</hi> Servant-Maid, yet he expreſs'd a tender Regard to the Near<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs of the Relation, by order<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing ſuch a Clauſe to be inſerted in the Settlement, as might be a <hi>ſaving to ſuch Sons as the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Lord</hi> Kingſton <hi>ſhould beget on the Body of ſuch a Wife as he ſhould Marry, with the Advice and Conſent of his ſaid Brother, and his Uncle Sir</hi> Robert King, <hi>or ſuch of his next Relations as ſhould be then living,</hi> &amp;c. And ſurely the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> had no cauſe to believe that his Brother would think it unreaſonable, that the Children of that Wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man,
<pb n="115" facs="tcp:60711:58"/>
whom, in his Letter to Mr. <hi>Goſling,</hi> he acknowledg'd to have been a <hi>Scullian,</hi> ſhould be barr'd from Inheriting a <hi>Lord's Eſtate.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And as we may perceive, by Mr. <hi>Goſling</hi>'s Depoſition, that the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> did ſolemnly declare his Intention of Settling his Eſtate on Cap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain <hi>Francis King,</hi> if his Uncle ſhould obſtinately perſiſt in the Refuſal of it; ſo the preſent Lord was ſo fully perſuaded of the Stedfaſtneſs of thoſe his Brother's Reſolutions, that when he came to Age, he <hi>freely,</hi> and of his own Accord, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clar'd his <hi>Conſent</hi> to his Uncle's <hi>Acceptance</hi> of his Brother's E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtate, which the late Lord <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton</hi>
               <pb n="116" facs="tcp:60711:59"/>
had before very frequently offer'd, and earneſtly preſs'd, and Sir <hi>Robert</hi> had as often, and obſtinately refus'd: For when Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> was going for <hi>England,</hi> in <hi>February</hi> 1683/4. the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> was pleaſed to favour him with his Company to <hi>Rings-End,</hi> and on the way, the preſent Lord, without any Connexion with their former Diſcourſe, addreſt himſelf to his Uncle in theſe, or the like Words, <hi>Uncle, when I was under Age, you refus'd to accept of the Eſtate offer'd you by my Brother; but now I am come to Age, I freely conſent to your Acceptance of it.</hi> The Truth of this Sir <hi>Robert</hi> is ready to depoſe, and has alſo the Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtimony
<pb n="117" facs="tcp:60711:59"/>
of Doctor <hi>Horneck</hi> to confirm it; for in his <note n="*" place="margin">Vid. <hi>Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pend.</hi> No. 10. <hi>Dr.</hi> Horneck<hi>'s Letter.</hi>
               </note> Letter to Sir <hi>Robert,</hi> dated <hi>Sept.</hi> 22. in the Year in which he died, he declares, That <hi>the preſent Lord</hi> Kingſton <hi>did acknowledge to him, that he had given his Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent to the paſſing his Brother's Eſtate to his Uncle.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Yet notwithſtanding this ſo voluntary, and ſo ſeemingly a deliberate a Tender, which the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> made his Uncle, of his Title to, and Intereſt in his Brother's Eſtate, Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> was ſtill ſcru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pulous in Accepting of it, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>til he had ſtated his Caſe to Four of the moſt Eminent Divines in <hi>England,</hi> (whom he conſulted a-part, without Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quainting
<pb n="118" facs="tcp:60711:60"/>
any one of them of his having had the Advice of any other) and had receiv'd their unanimous Agreement in their Opinions of the Lawful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs of his Acceptance of ſuch a Settlement.</p>
            <p>And to convince the Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der that Sir <hi>Robert</hi> did not (as the Libeller moſt groundleſsly ſuggeſts) <hi>State his Caſe after his own Way,</hi> but with all Faithful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs and Truth, I here produce it in the very Words in which he propounded it to the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Divines, as may appear by the Original ſign'd by them.</p>
            <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="statement">
               <body>
                  <p>A. <hi>having a fair Eſtate, Two Sons, and one Brother, dies; the Younger Brother having an Eſtate</hi>
                     <pb n="119" facs="tcp:60711:60"/>
                     <hi>of Five Hundred Pounds a Year, from his Mother's Father, Marries, about Eighteen, an</hi> Iriſh <hi>Papiſt Servant in his Brother's Family; on which, the Elder deſires to ſettle his Eſtate, after his own Iſſue, on his Uncle, and his Iſſue, and cut off the Brother: But the Uncle has for ſome time declin'd the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſal, on the ſcore of Conſcience, until the Younger's coming to Age, who, ſenſible of the Diſparagement brought upon his Family by his mean Marriage, has deſir'd his Uncle to accept the Offer; yet ſtill the Uncle continues ſcrupulous, and begs to know, whether in good Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcience he may Accept, or is bound to Refuſe the Eſtate ſo offer'd. The Younger Brother has by this Girl one or more Sons.</hi> And
<pb n="120" facs="tcp:60711:61"/>
they gave their Opinion in the following Words: <hi>The Caſe being ſo, as is propounded, my Opi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nion is, That the Uncle may, with a good Conſcience, Accept, and is not bound, by any Rule of Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcience that I know, to Refuſe ſuch a Settlement.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <closer>
                     <signed>John Ceſtrienſis.</signed>


                  </closer>
                  <postscript>
                     <p>
                        <hi>I ſee no Reaſon why he may not Accept, or why he ſhould think himſelf bound in Conſcience to Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſe the Eſtate ſo offer'd.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>John Tillotſon.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </postscript>
                  <postscript>
                     <p>
                        <hi>I am of the ſame Opinion.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Edward Stillingfleet.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </postscript>
                  <postscript>
                     <p>
                        <hi>I am of the ſame Opinion.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>John Sharp.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </postscript>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
            <p>
               <pb n="121" facs="tcp:60711:61"/>
Nor is the Libeller leſs mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtaken in what he ſuggeſts con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning the <hi>Time,</hi> than in what he ſays of the <hi>Manner</hi> of Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s <hi>Stating his Caſe</hi> to the Divines; for tho' he inti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mates, that he had not ask'd their Opinions before he had actually accepted of the Eſtate, yet the Truth of the whole Matter is plainly this, which Sir <hi>Robert</hi> is ready to depoſe; Sir <hi>Robert</hi> going for <hi>England</hi> in <hi>February</hi> 1681/4. at his firſt Landing there, waited on Doctor <hi>Pearſon,</hi> then Lord Biſhop of <hi>Cheſter,</hi> and conſul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted him concerning the fore-mention'd State of his Caſe, who then writ, and ſign'd his Opinion thereon; and when
<pb n="122" facs="tcp:60711:62"/>
he came to <hi>London,</hi> he diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cours'd the ſeveral other Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vines above-mention'd, (who all concurr'd in their Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments with the Biſhop of <hi>Cheſter)</hi> before he conſented to the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s leaving him next in Remainder to his Eſtate. But afterwards, in his Return for <hi>Ireland,</hi> conceiving it fit to have all their Opinions in Writing, he ſent the Original Caſe, with the Biſhop of <hi>Che<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter</hi>'s Hand to it, to Mr. <hi>Ray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mond,</hi> who was then in <hi>London,</hi> to get the reſt to Sign what before they had declar'd, which accordingly they freely did.</p>
            <p>But, beſides the great and undeniable Evidences I have already produc'd, to prove the
<pb n="123" facs="tcp:60711:62"/>
Falſeneſs of the Libeller's Sug<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>geſtion, <hi>That Sir</hi> Robert King <hi>endeavour'd, by all the Artifices he could invent, to procure the Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>heriſon of the preſent Lord,</hi> I ſhall mention two, which I may reaſonably preſume are beyond Exception: The firſt is, The Teſtimony of the late Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> who, in his Directi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons to draw an Anſwer to his Brother's Caſe preſented to the Houſe of Lords in <hi>England,</hi> declares, in a Paper <note n="*" place="margin">Vid. <hi>Appendix</hi> No. 11. <hi>The late Lord</hi> Kingſton<hi>'s Paper.</hi>
               </note> under his own Hand, ready to be produc'd, That <hi>the firſt Riſe of his Brother's Wife</hi> (the preſent Lady <hi>Kingſton) was, to be his Poultry Woman's Servant, and her greateſt, to be his Dairy-Maid, till ſhe became his,</hi> viz. <hi>his Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther's</hi>
               <pb n="124" facs="tcp:60711:63"/>
               <hi>Spouſe:</hi> And then follow theſe remarkable Words; <hi>That it was on this Occaſion I ſettled my Eſtate from him, and his Heirs, into a Family of good Extraction, and not, as he moſt unjuſtly ſays, by the Advice and Deſire of Sir</hi> Robert King, <hi>my Uncle, who was the only Man of all thoſe that knew my Deſigns, that oppos'd ſo juſt a Settlement.</hi> To this may be added the late Lord's <note n="*" place="margin">Vide <hi>Appendix</hi> No. 20. <hi>The late Lords Letter to Sir</hi> Robert King.</note> Letter, dated <hi>June</hi> 29. 1688. in which he ſays, <hi>If I could more firmly ſettle what I have, I would, and rivet it, rather than it ſhould be ever alter'd.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And if any Teſtimony in this Caſe may be imagin'd greater, than that of the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s, it muſt be
<pb n="125" facs="tcp:60711:63"/>
that of a profeſs'd Adverſary to Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> and even this I have to produce for Sir <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert</hi>'s further Vindication: For the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf, after his publickly known and avow'd Marriage, and even after his having the certain knowledge of his own <hi>Excluſion</hi> out of his Brother's Settlement, writ a Letter <note n="*" place="margin">Vide <hi>Appendix</hi> No. 14. <hi>The preſent Lord</hi> Kingſton<hi>'s Letter</hi>
               </note> without date, but ſome time in Summer 1684, to Sir <hi>Robert,</hi> who was then in <hi>England,</hi> wherein he was ſo far from Accuſing Sir <hi>Robert</hi> of <hi>Promoting</hi> his unfor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tunate Marriage, or of having done him <hi>ill Offices</hi> with his Brother, or of being an Inſtru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of his <hi>Diſheriſon,</hi> that he profeſſes a great <hi>Reſpect</hi> to
<pb n="126" facs="tcp:60711:64"/>
him, ſtiles him his <hi>dear Uncle,</hi> and declares, <hi>It was not want of Duty, that he had not waited upon him; acknowledges the Kindneſſes of his Relations, and confeſſes that bitter Reproaches were due to him from them; and that he was re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolv'd to live private, and retir'd from the Sight of all his Rela<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions and Friends;</hi> and ends that Letter with ſeemingly ſincere and hearty Promiſes of perpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tual Dutifulneſs to his Uncle, in theſe words; <hi>And tho' per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>haps you may never ſee me, yet as far as my Power ſhall ever reach, you ſhall ever find me your Du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiful and Obedient Nephew.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And now having, as I hope, very fully anſwer'd the Libel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ler's main Objections againſt
<pb n="127" facs="tcp:60711:64"/>
Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> relating to the Diſcharge of his Office of <hi>Guar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dian</hi> to his Nephews, and to the Circumſtances of the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s <hi>Marriage,</hi> and the late Lord's <hi>Settlement of his Eſtate,</hi> the remaining Objections will be more eaſily diſpatch'd. For, firſt, to what the Libeller ſuggeſts againſt Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> That <hi>he ſo wrought his Ends with the late Lord</hi> Kingſton, <hi>as to get him to ſettle</hi> 600 l. <hi>or</hi> 800 l. per An. <hi>of the New Eſtate upon him;</hi> the Anſwer is plain and eaſie; for 'tis very notorious, that the Eſtate, which the Libeller means, was not ſettled on Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> by the late Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> but by his Father, Sir <hi>Robert King</hi>'s Brother.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="128" facs="tcp:60711:65"/>
And here Sir <hi>Robert</hi> takes Occaſion, with all Gratitude, to acknowledge his Brother's extraordinary Kindneſs to him; for whereas his own Patrimony was but ſmall, his Brother, the late <hi>John</hi> Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> was pleaſed to ſettle on him, and his Heirs, by a Rentcharge, 400 <hi>l. per Annum,</hi> in order to his Marrying an Heireſs of an equivalent Fortune; and Sir <hi>Robert</hi> does freely own, that after his Brother's Deceaſe, his Executors and Truſtees did accordingly ſet out Lands out of the New Eſtate, to the Va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lue of 400 <hi>l. per Annum,</hi> in lieu of the Rentcharge for that Sum on the whole Eſtate: By which the Reader may perceive the
<pb n="129" facs="tcp:60711:65"/>
Ingenuity of the Libeller, not only in Advancing 400 <hi>l.</hi> into 600 <hi>l.</hi> or 800 <hi>l. per Annum,</hi> but alſo in Repreſenting that as the Effect of Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s <hi>Artifice,</hi> and <hi>Influence</hi> over his Nephew, the late Lord <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton,</hi> which was purely the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſult of his Brother, the late Lord <hi>John</hi>'s Generoſity.</p>
            <p>And as to the Objection concerning <hi>Sir</hi> Robert<hi>'s and Mr.</hi> Raymond<hi>'s Incenſing the late Lord</hi> Kingſton <hi>againſt his Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, on Account of his not Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turning the Papers relating to the Mannor of</hi> Newcaſtle, <hi>which he had got from Dr.</hi> Quail; the true State of that Matter is plainly this; Mr. <hi>Raymond</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing appointed a Truſtee by the
<pb n="130" facs="tcp:60711:66"/>
preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Grand-Father, Sir <hi>William Fenton,</hi> in ſeveral Deeds made by him of his Eſtate in <hi>Munſter,</hi> (of which <hi>Newcaſtle</hi> was a part) and having depoſited the Writings relating to that Intereſt in the Hands of his Son in Law, Dr. <hi>Quail,</hi> the preſent Lord pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vail'd with the Doctor to ſend him the Writings that concern'd <hi>New-Caſtle,</hi> on Promiſe of Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtoring them when requir'd, which his Lordſhip afterwards refuſing to do, Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> knowing that the late Lord had a Remainder in that Eſtate, advis'd Mr. <hi>Raymond</hi> to ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quaint his Lordſhip with the Damage he might ſuffer by thoſe Papers being detain'd by
<pb n="131" facs="tcp:60711:66"/>
his Brother, and not lodg'd (as they ought to be) in the hands of the Truſtee: And this being the plain and whole Truth of that Caſe, the Libeller ſurely had no reaſon to repreſent Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s Juſtice to the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> as an ill Office to the preſent Lord.</p>
            <p>Nor has the Libeller more reaſon to reproach Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> for <hi>Adviſing the late Lord</hi> Kingſton, <hi>immediately after the late Revolution, to ſettle and ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ply</hi> Newcaſtle <hi>to pious Uſes;</hi> for tho' that Mannor was left to the preſent Lord, by his Grand-Father, Sir <hi>William Fen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton;</hi> yet his Lordſhip being at that time a Forfeiting Perſon, on account of his adherence
<pb n="132" facs="tcp:60711:67"/>
to, and continuance with the late King in <hi>France,</hi> and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſequently, in no Capacity of Enjoying it, and his Brother, the late Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> having Pretenſions to that Eſtate, (as being in Remainder in the Set<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlement, as well as Heir at Law) Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s <hi>Adviſing the late Lord to diſpoſe of it to the Poor,</hi> cannot reaſonably be in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terpreted as an <hi>Injuſtice</hi> or <hi>Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſervice</hi> to the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Nor is Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> ſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>licitous to make any Defence for his Oppoſing <hi>the Reverſal of the preſent Lord's Outlawry;</hi> for his Lordſhip having, not only ſome Years before the late Revolution, publickly <hi>renounc'd</hi>
               <pb n="133" facs="tcp:60711:67"/>
the Proteſtant Religion, but alſo for ſome time ſince <hi>profeſt</hi> himſelf a Papiſt, and having left his Lady and Children in <hi>France,</hi> as Hoſtages of his firm Adherence and Fidelity to the late King, Sir <hi>Robert</hi> thought himſelf oblig'd to lay this Mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter before the Government: The Conſideration of which being referr'd to the then So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>licitor General Sir <hi>Richard Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving,</hi> he declar'd it as his Opi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nion, That it was not ſafe for the Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> to <hi>Reverſe his Outlawry,</hi> until he had brought over his Lady and Children into His Majeſty's Dominions, in Order to their being Educated Proteſtants: On which the Lord <hi>Capell,</hi> the
<pb n="134" facs="tcp:60711:68"/>
then Lord-Deputy of this Kingdom, (judging it a Bu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſineſs of Conſequence) thought fit to tranſmit it into <hi>England;</hi> whereupon the <hi>Reverſal</hi> of the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lawry was ſtopt, till his Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip's Eldeſt Son came to <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> and he had ſent into <hi>France</hi> for the reſt of his Family. And here we may take an Eſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mate of the Libeller's Loyalty to His Majeſty, and of his Regard to the publick Good, by his blaming Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> for not preferring his Nephew's private Advantage to the Safety of the Kingdom, and Security of the Proteſtant Religion.</p>
            <p>Nor is that more fairly re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſented by the Libeller, which
<pb n="135" facs="tcp:60711:68"/>
he writes concerning <hi>the late Lord</hi> Kingſton<hi>'s Promiſe to the late King, to leave the Matters in Controverſie between him and his Brother, as they were in the Ori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ginal Settlement:</hi> For that which the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mis'd the late King <hi>James,</hi> was not, as the Libeller inſinuates, to make him Heir to his Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip's Eſtate, but only to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinue him in the peaceable Poſſeſſion of the <hi>Mannor of Newcaſtle,</hi> to which, as being Heir at Law, the late Lord had fair Pretenſions; all which Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> is ready to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe.</p>
            <p>And as to what is objected concerning Sir <hi>Robert King</hi>'s <hi>being inform'd by Dean</hi> Cope <hi>of</hi>
               <pb n="136" facs="tcp:60711:69"/>
               <hi>ſome Papers left by the late Lord</hi> Kingſton <hi>for the Uſe of his Brother, and Sir</hi> Robert<hi>'s endea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vouring to ſuppreſs them;</hi> the Occaſion of that unjuſt Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>proach was only this: Dean <hi>Cope</hi> having acquainted Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> that there was a Report in the Country of ſome Papers being left by the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> at his Death, not for the Uſe of his Brother, (as the Libeller ſuggeſts) but of his Lady, Sir <hi>Robert</hi> writ to the Dean from <hi>Dublin,</hi> to take all poſſible Care to have them tranſmitted to the preſent At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torney-General, Truſtee for the Lady <hi>Kingſton;</hi> but the Dean, after the ſtricteſt Enquiry he could make, could find no
<pb n="137" facs="tcp:60711:69"/>
ſuch Papers, and diſcover'd the Report relating to 'em to be altogether falſe and ground<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs.</p>
            <p>As to what is offer'd from the late Lady <hi>Dowager King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton</hi>'s Anſwer to a Bill fil'd a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt her by Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> namely, <hi>That her Lord declar'd to her, that he was ſorry he had made ſuch a Settlement, and that he had deſigns to alter it;</hi> It is anſwer'd, That Sir <hi>Robert,</hi> out of Reſpect to her Memory, being willing to ſuppoſe the Truth of what her Ladyſhip has averr'd, has nevertheleſs good reaſon to believe, that tho' his Lordſhip might per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>haps, in ſome ſudden heat, expreſs himſelf to that purpoſe,
<pb n="138" facs="tcp:60711:70"/>
on occaſion of Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s plain dealing with him in other Matters, yet his Lordſhip ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver did, upon ſerious Thoughts, ſhew any diſlike of that Settle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment; for as it is obſervable, that her Ladyſhip does not, in her Anſwer to Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s Bill, give the leaſt hint of her Lord's deſigning to ſettle any part of his Eſtate on his Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther; ſo it is generally known, and has been publickly atte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſted by Perſons <note n="*" place="margin">Vid. <hi>Mr.</hi> Connelly<hi>'s Depoſition in the Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pend.</hi> No. 13</note> of good Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dit, who were moſt conver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſant with him, that in his Lordſhip's conſtant Diſcourſe he declar'd himſelf <hi>highly pleas'd with the Settlement</hi> he had made, and did alſo in his laſt Sick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs declare <hi>his Fears, that his</hi>
               <pb n="139" facs="tcp:60711:70"/>
               <hi>Uncle's eaſie Temper would incline him to act contrary</hi> to his Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip's full Deſign, and the pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port of the Deed which he had made.</p>
            <p>And as touching the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended <hi>Declaration</hi> and <hi>Deed</hi> of the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>voking the Settlement made in the Year 1689, and granting his Eſtate to his Brother, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> does not in the leaſt doubt but that he ſhall be able, when there is Occa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion, to make good his Title againſt all pretended <hi>Declara<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions, Deeds,</hi> and <hi>Revocations,</hi> that have been ſet up ſince the late Lord's Death, and againſt all other Pretenſions whatſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="140" facs="tcp:60711:71"/>
But that the Reader may the better judge of the Credi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bility of theſe Pretences, it will not be improper to inform him, that it appears by an Affidavit, ready to be produc'd, That conſiderable Rewards were promis'd to a Clerk belonging to the <hi>Common-Pleas,</hi> to imbezil or raze two Writs of Cove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant which belonged to two Fines levied of the <hi>Boyle</hi> Eſtate by <hi>Robert</hi> the late Lord <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton,</hi> and that theſe Propoſals were made by <hi>Daniel Sullevane,</hi> a Perſon who was then in the Intereſts of the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And it has been alſo fully and publickly prov'd, that in the Year 1695, when Mr. <hi>Ray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mond</hi>
               <pb n="141" facs="tcp:60711:71"/>
was in <hi>Dublin,</hi> and was ſuppos'd to have Sir <hi>Robert King</hi>'s Papers with him there, ſeveral profligate Perſons, of the Name of <hi>Sullevane,</hi> (one of which then waited on the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton)</hi> cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupted Mr. <hi>Raymond</hi>'s Servant, to ſteal away his Maſter's Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pers, which he accordingly did; and the whole Matter being plainly detected, one of the Perſon's concern'd being taken, was Pillory'd, and the reſt fled: And it was remark<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able on the Tryal, that it was prov'd that they gave the Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vant a ſtrict Charge to ſearch for a Paper, containing a Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charge, or general Releaſe, given by the preſent Lord
<pb n="142" facs="tcp:60711:72"/>
               <hi>Kingſton</hi> to Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> for his Guardianſhip.</p>
            <p>And to this purpoſe it is obſervable, That in the time of the late War, when Sir <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert King</hi> was in <hi>England,</hi> the preſent Lord came to a faithful old Servant, of Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> at <hi>Rockingham,</hi> and perſuaded her to deliver him the Papers ſhe had of Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s, and promis'd he would keep them ſafe for him, and on that Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tence got them into his Hands, and never would afterwards reſtore them; all which is fully depos'd upon Oath. <note n="*" place="margin">Vid. <hi>Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pend.</hi> No. 14 Nola Mur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phey<hi>'s Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fidavit.</hi>
               </note>
            </p>
            <p>Now to what is objected concerning <hi>Sir</hi> Rober King<hi>'s and Captain</hi> Choppine<hi>'s offering to buy</hi> Sligoe, <hi>and to put</hi> 2000 l.
<pb n="143" facs="tcp:60711:72"/>
               <hi>in his Lordſhip's Pocket, on Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dition he would make an abſolute Deed, and put Sir</hi> Robert King <hi>into the actual Poſſeſſion of his whole Eſtate;</hi> the Anſwer is ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry plain: For as Sir <hi>Robert</hi> was never known to be a Pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaſer; ſo it cannot reaſona<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly be imagin'd, that Captain <hi>Choppine,</hi> who bequeath'd Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> nothing at the time of his Death, would have made ſo great a Purchace for him in his Life time.</p>
            <p>And it's hardly worth men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioning what is objected con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning Sir <hi>Robert King's Build<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings at</hi> Rockingham, viz. <hi>That they were ſo Sumptuous, as to bear no Proportion to his Eſtate; and therefore, that it may be well in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferr'd,</hi>
               <pb n="144" facs="tcp:60711:73"/>
               <hi>That Sir</hi> Robert <hi>had Deſigns all along on</hi> Boyle <hi>and</hi> Michelſtown: For ſuppoſing we ſhould grant what the Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beller ſuggeſts, concerning the Greatneſs of Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s Houſe, (which none that have ſeen it will allow) yet the Inference he draws from thence is alto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether groundleſs, and unrea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonable: For tho' Mens Build<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing beyond their Fortune has been frequently eſteem'd an Argument of their Impru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence, yet ſcarcely ever of their Covetouſneſs; it being often known, that many have Built themſelves out of their own Eſtates, but ſeldom or never into thoſe of other Men.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="145" facs="tcp:60711:73"/>
And as Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> gave many ſignal Proofs of his <hi>Affe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction</hi> to the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Perſon, ſo alſo he plainly de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monſtrated his ſincere <hi>deſire,</hi> that his Eſtate ſhould deſcend to his Iſſue: For even after the perfection of that <hi>Settle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment,</hi> by which Sir <hi>Robert</hi> and his Sons were Nam'd next in Remainder to the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> and his Iſſue, Sir <hi>Robert</hi> was ſo far from being tempted by the proſpect of Advantage, to uſe any <hi>Artifice</hi> o divert his Lordſhip from the thoughts of Marriage, that the very conſideration of his kindneſs in that <hi>Settlement</hi> did move Sir <hi>Robert</hi> to be more than ordinary Solicitous to
<pb n="146" facs="tcp:60711:74"/>
provide his Lordſhip a good Wife, and accordingly, by the Advice and with the Aſſiſtance of the late Lord Arch-Biſhop of <hi>Canterbury,</hi> Dr. <hi>Tillotſon,</hi> he endeavoured to procure for him the Lord <hi>Hatton</hi>'s Daugh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, who was his only Child, and had 10000 <hi>l.</hi> for her Por<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, beſides the expectation of her Father's Eſtate; but tho' the Lord <hi>Hatton</hi> himſelf gave ſome Encouragement to the Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Courting his Daughter, yet the young Lady's Relations by her Mother's ſide being unwilling ſhe ſhould leave <hi>England,</hi> the Match was broke off.</p>
            <p>Some time after this, Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> advis'd the late
<pb n="147" facs="tcp:60711:74"/>
Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> to make his Addreſſes to the Lady <hi>Elizabeth Cromwell,</hi> of the Kingdom of <hi>Ireland,</hi> and with his Lordſhip's Approbation, had ſeveral Treaties with the young Ladies Relations, and had ſuch En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>couragement given him to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinue his Solicitations of this Match, that it was once thought to be very near a Concluſion, when on a ſudden, the young Lady chang'd her Mind, and to Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s great ſurprize and concern, all his endea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vours to carry on that Deſign, prov'd ineffectual.</p>
            <p>And not long after this, there being a Propoſal made for the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Courting of Mr. <hi>Harbord</hi>'s
<pb n="148" facs="tcp:60711:75"/>
Daughter, Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> did not only give his free <hi>Conſent</hi> to his Lordſhips making his Addreſſes to that Lady, but did alſo heartily <hi>Negotiate</hi> that Affair, and at length brought it to a happy Iſſue.</p>
            <p>And laſtly, to ſhew the groundleſſneſs of the Libeller's Suggeſtion, that Sir <hi>Robert King, on the late Lord</hi> Kingſton<hi>'s Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riage, gave directions for the mak<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing a new Settlement of that Lord's Eſtate, plying him with Company at the Tavern for Eight days to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether, and Incenſing him all the while againſt his Brother, till that Settlement was perfected, and Sir</hi> Robert <hi>had got himſelf and his Children nam'd next in Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mainder, after the late Lord and</hi>
               <pb n="149" facs="tcp:60711:75"/>
               <hi>his Iſſue, excluding his Brother:</hi> I ſhall produce Mr. <hi>Raymond</hi>'s Teſtimony on Oath, <note n="*" place="margin">Vid. <hi>Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pend. Mr.</hi> Raymond<hi>'s Depoſition.</hi> No. 15.</note> who declares that Sir <hi>Robert King, being inform'd that the late Lord</hi> Kingſton <hi>had commanded Mr.</hi> Raymond <hi>to provide a new Deed of Settlement to be Drawn, in or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der to his Marriage, ſent him to acquaint his Lordſhip, that by the former Deed of Settlement he had made, his Eſtate was, for want of Iſſue of his own Body, to go to Sir</hi> Robert King <hi>and his Sons, but that by a Proviſo in that Settlement there was a Power reſerv'd to his Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip, ſome Months before and after his Marriage, to Revoke that Deed, and make ſuch a Settlement of his Eſtate as he ſhould think fit, and therefore deſir'd his Lordſhip ſeri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ouſly</hi>
               <pb n="150" facs="tcp:60711:76"/>
               <hi>to conſider with himſelf, and alſo to conſult ſome eminent Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vines in the City of</hi> London, <hi>whether he was not oblig'd in Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcience to Settle his Eſtate on his Brother, when it was in his Power; becauſe if there were a new Deed, and Settlement made upon his Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riage, with the like Uſes and Limi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tations as in the former, it would not be in his Power to revoke it. This Meſsage Mr.</hi> Raymond <hi>Swears, he faithfully deliver'd from Sir</hi> Robert King, <hi>to the late Lord</hi> Kingſton, <hi>who commanded him to acquaint his Uncle, that he deſir'd him not to trouble himſelf any more in that Matter, becauſe he was fully reſolv'd to continue the former Settlement as it was, or to Settle the Eſtate on Sir</hi> Robert<hi>'s Sons, if he refus'd it.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="151" facs="tcp:60711:76"/>
And now I do not doubt but that every judicious and impartial Reader will be fully perſwaded that no juſt Refle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction can be made, either on the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Honor in Settling his Eſtate on his Uncle, or on Sir <hi>Robert King</hi>'s Juſtice in accepting it; for tho' his Lordſhip was pleaſed to <hi>Exclude</hi> his Brother, yet 'tis very plain, that he did it on ſuch weighty Conſiderations as would undoubtedly prevail with every Proteſtant Noble<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man to <hi>Diſinherit</hi> his only Son: And tho' Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> did permit himſelf to be Nam'd next in Remainder to the late Lord and his Iſſue in that Settlement that was Revokable,
<pb n="152" facs="tcp:60711:77"/>
yet he did it not, (as has been plainly prov'd) till the preſent Lord had not only <hi>freely given his Conſent to his Uncle's accep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tance of the Eſtate,</hi> but had alſo vilely <hi>proſtituted</hi> his own, and his Families Honour by his <hi>Ignoble Marriage.</hi> But the grand Reaſons that provok'd the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> to Exclude his Brother out of the final and irrevokable <hi>Settlement,</hi> perfect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed ſome time before his Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riage, were the unworthy <hi>Aſper<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſions</hi> that he caſt on him in his Petition to the late King, and in his Addreſs to the Houſe of Lords in <hi>England,</hi> and his open <hi>renouncing</hi> the Proteſtant Reli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gion, and his avow'd <hi>Adherence</hi> to the late King <hi>James</hi>'s Inte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſts.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="153" facs="tcp:60711:77"/>
As touching the laſt Head of the Libeller's <hi>Materials for a Bill of Diſcovery againſt Sir</hi> Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert King, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> which con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerns Matter of <hi>Title,</hi> and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſts of a Recital of ſeveral <hi>Deeds</hi> of Settlement, and other <hi>Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyances,</hi> Sir <hi>Robert</hi> thinks it im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>proper for him to make any particular Defence in this Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per, all thoſe things being now referr'd, by Conſent of Parties, to the <hi>Arbitrement</hi> of ſome of the Reverend Judges, and to the <hi>Umpirage</hi> of his Excellency the Lord <hi>Golloway.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And as I have good reaſon to hope, that their Determina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of that Controverſie will be in Sir <hi>Robert King</hi>'s favour, ſo I don't queſtion but that,
<pb n="154" facs="tcp:60711:78"/>
by the <hi>Anſwers</hi> that have been return'd to the Libeller's moſt invidious <hi>Suggeſtions,</hi> Sir <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert</hi>'s <hi>Innocency</hi> will be fully vindicated, and that it will ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear to every intelligent and ingenuous Reader, that no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing could reaſonably be ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pected from an <hi>Affectionate Un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cle,</hi> from a <hi>Faithful Guardian,</hi> from a <hi>Grateful Brother,</hi> and from a <hi>Prudent</hi> and <hi>Good Man,</hi> which Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> has not done for his Brother's Sons, the late and preſent Lord <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="appendix">
            <pb n="155" facs="tcp:60711:78"/>
            <head>APPENDIX.</head>
            <div n="1" type="oath">
               <head>N<hi rend="sup">o.</hi> I. Anthony Raymond, <hi>
                     <abbr>Esq</abbr> his Oath.</hi>
               </head>
               <p n="1">1. <hi>ANthony Raymond,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Esq</abbr> came this Day before Me, and made Oath, That he does not remember, that the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Father did deſign and direct that the late Lord <hi>Arran</hi> and Sir <hi>Robert Booth</hi> ſhould, after his Death, be Guardians to the late, and preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton;</hi> and that he did not uſe any Arti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice
<pb n="156" facs="tcp:60711:79"/>
to perſwade them to chooſe their Uncle, Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> for their Guardian; <hi>nor was he</hi> (that he remembers) <hi>ever de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſired by the ſaid Sir</hi> Robert King <hi>to move them to it,</hi> but what he adviſed in that par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticular was for their good.</p>
               <p n="2">2. That he knew of no <hi>ill Deſigns of Sir</hi> Robert King on his Nephews, but that, on the contrary, he always promoted their Good, and Advantage; and that he, this Deponent, ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver did enter into <hi>Combination</hi> with the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert,</hi> Cap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain <hi>Caulfield,</hi> Doctor <hi>Cope,</hi> Mr. <hi>Goſling,</hi> and <hi>Francis Quail,</hi> to deprive the late or preſent Lord of their Eſtates, or to do any thing to their Prejudice, but
<pb n="157" facs="tcp:60711:79"/>
was active to promote their Intereſts, as appears by ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Inſtances well known to many.</p>
               <p n="3">3. This Deponent further declares, That he always ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerv'd a great Zeal in Sir <hi>Robert</hi> to perſuade the late Lord <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton</hi> to an honourable Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riage; that he was often em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ploy'd by the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> to bring the ſame to ef<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fect, and particularly remem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers, that, being in <hi>London,</hi> the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert</hi> was inform'd of one Madam <hi>Holland,</hi> an Heireſs of an Eſtate worth 800 <hi>l. per Annum</hi> old Rent, as he remembers, near <hi>Mancheſter;</hi> whereupon he the Deponent, with a Friend that had ſome
<pb n="158" facs="tcp:60711:80"/>
Intereſt and Acquaintance in that Family, were order'd by the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert</hi> to viſit the Lady, and inquire into the Truth of Matters, as to her Fortune and Perſon, and from thence this Deponent was di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rected to go and give the late Lord an account of it, then in <hi>Ireland,</hi> which he did accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dingly, and which ſo far pleas'd his Lordſhip, that he fully re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolv'd to make Court to the ſaid Madam <hi>Holland,</hi> prepar'd for his Journey, and pitch'd on Mr. <hi>Adam Purdon</hi> for his Companion, and order'd the Deponent to go before, to pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pare things, which he did; but when this Deponent came there, he found that the Lady
<pb n="159" facs="tcp:60711:80"/>
was too far engag'd, a Match being as good as concluded on with another.</p>
               <p n="4">4. That he was by the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> ſent into the <hi>North,</hi> to a Place (as he re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>members) call'd <hi>Bangor,</hi> to one Mr. <hi>Hamilton,</hi> as he be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieves, Uncle to the Lady <hi>Betty Cromwell,</hi> to give an account of the late Lord's Eſtate, in order to a Match that was on foot betwixt the ſaid Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> and the Lady <hi>Betty Cromwell;</hi> and that afterwards being in <hi>London,</hi> the Matter was ſo far proſecuted, that Deeds were a preparing in or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der to a Concluſion of a Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riage, which the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert ſeem'd to this Deponent to be very</hi>
                  <pb n="160" facs="tcp:60711:81"/>
                  <hi>intent, and earneſt for;</hi> but by ſome occaſion it broke off.</p>
               <p n="5">5. This Deponent further depoſeth, That he does <hi>not remember to have receiv'd</hi> any Letter from Captain <hi>Choppine,</hi> bearing date the <hi>17th</hi> of <hi>June,</hi> 1684. wherein theſe Expreſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſions are; <hi>That the Fire kind<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led muſt be kept alive by Sir</hi> Robert<hi>'s Friends: That an Op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portunity offers to make him and his Happy. I promiſe he will gratefully reward you,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
               <p n="6">6. That he very well re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>members, That on paſſing the Accounts of Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s Guar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dianſhip of the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> he the ſaid Lord did freely, and of his own accord, allow the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert King</hi>
                  <pb n="161" facs="tcp:60711:81"/>
                  <hi>One Hundred</hi> and <hi>Fifty Pounds</hi> for his Care and Charges in the Management of the ſaid Guardianſhip.</p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>Ant. Raymond.</signed>
                  <dateline>
                     <hi>Jurat coram me</hi> 
                     <date>15 <hi>die</hi> Auguſti, 1698.</date>
                  </dateline>
                  <signed>Ste. Moore.</signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <div n="2" type="deposition">
               <head>N<hi rend="sup">o.</hi> II. <hi>The Depoſition of Mrs.</hi> Elenor Sankey.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>ELenor Sankey,</hi> of the City of <hi>Dublin,</hi> Widow, came this Day before Me, and made Oath, That ſhe, this Depo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nent, being at Sir <hi>Robert King</hi>'s Houſe in <hi>Abby-Boyle</hi> about <hi>Chriſtmas,</hi> which was in the Year of our Lord 1678. the
<pb n="162" facs="tcp:60711:82"/>
preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> applied to her, this Deponent, in be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>half of his now Lady, ſaying, that he had a Complaint to make to her, and with Tears in his Eyes told this Deponent, That there was a poor inno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cent Girl in the Caſtle (mean<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Houſe) who was an Under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling, and he ſaw her a quiet Creature, and deſir'd Mrs. <hi>Horſey</hi> (who was then Houſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>keeper to the ſaid Lord <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton)</hi> to advance her to be his Chamber-Maid, which ſhe ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cordingly did, whereupon Mr. <hi>Goſling</hi> and ſome others ſaid, That he, the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> and the ſaid Girl, were too familiar, or too great,
<pb n="163" facs="tcp:60711:82"/>
as the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> then told this Deponent, ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding, that the reaſon of their Cenſuring her was, becauſe ſhe would not yield to them in any ill thing, and that they, like unjuſt People, had told his Uncle, Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> who was ſo incens'd againſt the ſaid Girl, that he was fully reſolv'd to turn her away, and had given Orders that ſhe ſhould be forthwith turn'd out of the Family. This Depo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nent further depoſeth, that the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> told her at the ſame time, That he knew that ſhe, this Deponent, had great Intereſt with the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> and begg'd her to uſe it, that the ſaid Girl
<pb n="164" facs="tcp:60711:83"/>
might not be put out of her Service; and to let Sir <hi>Robert,</hi> and all the World ſee her In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nocence, he would receive the Sacrament the day following on it; and further ſaid, He would not for any thing in the World have the Girl turn'd off, and loſe her Reputation by him, and begg'd her, this Deponent, to intercede for her with the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> which ſhe this Deponent did, but found Sir <hi>Robert</hi> ſo angry, and ſo reſolv'd to turn away the ſaid Girl, that ſhe would not venture to ſay much to him about her. This Depo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nent further depoſeth, That ſhe often heard that the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> was too
<pb n="165" facs="tcp:60711:83"/>
familiar with <hi>Peggy Cahan,</hi> but never heard nor thought that there was any Apprehenſion of his Lordſhip's Marrying her, while they were in <hi>Ireland.</hi> That this Deponent often heard likewiſe, that the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> offer'd to ſettle his Eſtate upon his Uncle, Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> on Report of <hi>Peggy Cahan</hi>'s being with the preſent Lord in <hi>France,</hi> or that ſhe was Married to him; but that Sir <hi>Robert</hi> often refus'd any ſuch Settlement, tho' ſhe, this Deponent, heard her Uncle and Aunt <hi>Choppine</hi> ſeveral times preſs him to accept of it.</p>
               <closer>
                  <dateline>
                     <hi>Jurat coram me</hi> 
                     <date>11 <hi>die</hi> Maii, 1699.</date>
                  </dateline>
                  <signed>Jo. Usſher.</signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <div n="3" type="affidavit">
               <pb n="166" facs="tcp:60711:84"/>
               <head>N<hi rend="sup">o.</hi> III. <hi>Dean</hi> Cope<hi>'s Affidavit.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>DOctor <hi>Anthony Cope,</hi> Dean of <hi>Elphin,</hi> came this day before Me, and made Oath, That Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> never re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>queſted this Deponent to move the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> to make any Settlement of his Eſtate upon him the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> and is morally aſſur'd he never did deſire any one elſe to ſtir in it: But, on the contrary, this Deponent hath often heard, that the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> delayed perfect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, or ſuffering to perfect, ſuch a Settlement by the late
<pb n="167" facs="tcp:60711:84"/>
Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> even to the Incenſing the ſaid Lord <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton,</hi> and that he was ſo ſcru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pulous, that he would not con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent that ſuch a Settlement ſhould be made, until he had conſulted the beſt Divines in <hi>England.</hi> And this Deponent further depoſeth, that he heard, from a credible Perſon, That the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert</hi> being ask'd by the late Lord, if he was yet reſolv'd to conſent to the mak<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing ſuch a Settlement, anſwer'd, That tho' he was ſatisfied it was lawful for him to accept of the Eſtate, yet he had ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther ſcruple, whether it was lawful for the ſaid Lord to give it; at which the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> flew into a Paſſion,
<pb n="168" facs="tcp:60711:85"/>
and ſaid, he would ſettle it upon Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s Eldeſt Son if Sir <hi>Robert</hi> would prove ſo ſhy, and ſlow in his Reſult. And this Deponent further de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſeth, That he never open'd his Mouth, nor did he ever mention the leaſt Syllable to the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> relating to the <hi>Diſinheriting</hi> his Brother, the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> or <hi>making over the Eſtate</hi> on Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> or his Heirs. And this Deponent further depoſeth, That the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> gave Directions, that the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Lady <hi>Kingſton</hi> (being then one of the Servant-Maids in the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Houſe) ſhould be diſcharg'd, having heard that there was too much
<pb n="169" facs="tcp:60711:85"/>
Familiarity between her, and the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton;</hi> whereupon the now Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> ſpoke to this Depo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nent, on the top of the Warren near the Town of <hi>Abby-Boyle,</hi> to <hi>intercede with his Uncle, Sir</hi> Robert King, <hi>for her Continu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance in her Service,</hi> urging, that the only way to prove the Report of her being with Child to be falſe, was to let her ſtay, and that would diſprove it; but if ſhe were ſent away, the People here would conclude it true. This Deponent further depoſeth, That after this Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courſe with the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> he, this Deponent, walk'd after the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> towards <hi>Ballindrehit,</hi> and
<pb n="170" facs="tcp:60711:86"/>
preſs'd him to grant what the ſaid Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> deſired, and after ſome pawſing the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert</hi> agreed to it, provided he, this Deponent, would go to Mrs. <hi>Horſey,</hi> (the Houſe-keeper) and deſire her ear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſtly to have a care, that, for the future, they were not too great, and if any thing happen'd amiſs, it ſhould lie at her door; all which this Deponent told the ſaid Mrs. <hi>Horſey.</hi>
               </p>
               <closer>
                  <dateline>
                     <hi>Jurat coram me</hi> 
                     <date>28 <hi>die</hi> Julii, <hi>An. Dom.</hi> 1698.</date>
                  </dateline>
                  <signed>John French.</signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <div n="4" type="oath">
               <pb n="171" facs="tcp:60711:86"/>
               <head>N<hi rend="sup">o.</hi> IV. <hi>The Right Honourable</hi> John <hi>Lord Baron of</hi> Kingſton, <hi>Plaintiff, Sir</hi> Robert King, <hi>Defendant.</hi> Charles Goſling, <hi>
                     <abbr>Esq</abbr> his Oath.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <hi>CHarles Goſling,</hi> of the City of <hi>Killkenny,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Esq</abbr> came this day before Me, and made Oath, That for ſeveral Years before the late Troubles, he having been in the Service of <hi>Robert</hi> late Lord Baron of <hi>Kingſton,</hi> the Plaintiff's Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, at <hi>Abby-Boyle,</hi> in the County of <hi>Roſcommon;</hi> and he this Deponent having obſerv'd, before the Plaintiff went to <hi>France,</hi> a more than ordinary
<pb n="172" facs="tcp:60711:87"/>
Familiarity between the Plain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiff (being then a younger Brother, and living in the Houſe) and one <hi>Margaret Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>han,</hi> then a Servant in the Houſe, who uſually made the Beds, he, this Deponent, acquainted Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> the Defendant, then the Plaintiff's Guardian, therewith; (the ſaid <hi>Robert</hi> Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> being then a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>broad in his Travels) and that Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendant, thereupon order'd one Mrs. <hi>Horſey,</hi> the then Houſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>keeper, and a Relation of the Family, to turn her out of the Houſe, who accordingly did ſo, and ſhe was for ſome time out of that Service, until by the <hi>Plaintiff's means ſhe was</hi>
                  <pb n="173" facs="tcp:60711:87"/>
                  <hi>brought in again by the ſaid Houſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>keeper, without the Conſent or Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vity of the Defendant,</hi> as this De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ponent verily believes; for that he heard the Defendant ſeverely reprimand and check the ſaid Mrs. <hi>Horſey,</hi> the Houſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>keeper, for ſo doing, tho' this Deponent did not then think, neither doth he believe it en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tred into the Defendant's Thoughts, that his Nephew, the Plaintiff, would ſo much debaſe himſelf and his Family, as to contract Marriage with her. This Deponent further depoſeth, That the Defendant, being then Guardian to the Plaintiff, and having a tender Care of him, to prevent any occaſion of Leudneſs or De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bauchery
<pb n="174" facs="tcp:60711:88"/>
between him and the ſaid <hi>Margaret,</hi> did <hi>endeavour to get one</hi> William Teams, <hi>then an Under-Cook in the Houſe, to Marry her, offering him, as a Portion with her, the Summ of Thirty Pounds</hi> ſterl. <hi>or there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>abouts,</hi> to the beſt of this De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ponent's Remembrance, which he doth in his Conſcience be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve was merely out of the Kindneſs and the tender Affe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction he had to the Plaintiff. This Deponent further depo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeth, That the Plaintiff ſoon after went for <hi>France,</hi> and took the ſaid <hi>Margaret Cahan</hi> with him, without the Conſent, Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vity or Knowledge, as this De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ponent verily believes, either of his Brother, the ſaid <hi>Robert,</hi>
                  <pb n="175" facs="tcp:60711:88"/>
then Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> or of his Uncle, the Defendant, until afterwards that Notice was ſent over from <hi>Paris</hi> in <hi>France,</hi> by one Captain <hi>Samuel Pach,</hi> the Plaintiff's then Tutor, or Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernour, giving an account that the ſaid <hi>Margaret Cahan</hi> was in <hi>Paris,</hi> kept, and main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained by the Plaintiff; upon which, ſuch Care was taken, that one Doctor <hi>Quail,</hi> a Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vine, (who had formerly Tra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vell'd into <hi>France</hi> with the ſaid <hi>Robert</hi> late Lord <hi>Kingſton) was ſent over to</hi> Paris, <hi>either to bring the Plaintiff back, or remove the ſaid</hi> Margaret <hi>from him;</hi> but the Plaintiff having Notice thereof, (as this Deponent was credibly inform'd) remov'd
<pb n="176" facs="tcp:60711:89"/>
with the ſaid <hi>Margaret</hi> from <hi>Paris,</hi> and then Married her the ſaid <hi>Margaret,</hi> as was cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dibly reported. This Depo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nent further depoſeth, That when the News came of the Plaintiff's being Married to the ſaid <hi>Margaret,</hi> the ſaid <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert,</hi> late Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> his Brother, was ſo much <hi>troubled at it, and ſo enraged againſt him, that he ſoon after reſolv'd to levy a Fine, and ſuffer a Recovery of his Eſtate</hi> both in <hi>Connaught</hi> and <hi>Munſter,</hi> and told his Uncle, the Defendant, of his Reſolu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, and that he would ſettle the ſame upon him, and his Children; and the Defendant thereupon <hi>advis'd him to the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary, telling him, that tho' his</hi>
                  <pb n="177" facs="tcp:60711:89"/>
                  <hi>Brother had Married ſo far be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neath himſelf, and his Family, yet ſhe might make a good Wife,</hi> or words to that effect; upon which the ſaid <hi>Robert,</hi> late Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> ſolemnly Proteſted, and Swore, <hi>That in Caſe the Defendant, Sir</hi> Robert King, <hi>would not accept of the Settlement, he would ſettle the Eſtate on his Couſin, Captain</hi> Francis King, <hi>and his Children,</hi> which this De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ponent often heard the ſaid late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> declare, and this Deponent does verily be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve <hi>that he would ſo have done, in caſe the ſaid Sir</hi> Robert <hi>had not accepted of the ſame.</hi> This Deponent further depoſeth, That after the Plaintiff was Married, as aforeſaid, he often
<pb n="178" facs="tcp:60711:90"/>
heard the <hi>Defendant very preſſing with</hi> Robert <hi>late Lord</hi> Kingſton, (the Plaintiff's Brother) <hi>to Marry, that he might have Iſſue to Inherit his Eſtate, and never gave over till he was actually Married;</hi> and doth verily believe in his Conſcience, that the Defendant was extreamly <hi>Troubled and Diſſatisfied, that the Plaintiff had Married ſo far beneath himſelf, and that it was done without the Defendant's Conſent, Knowledge, Privity, or Approbation.</hi>
               </p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>Char. Goſling.</signed>
                  <signed>
                     <hi>Cognoſco Deponentem,</hi> John Pape.</signed>
                  <dateline>Capt. &amp; Jurat cor. me apud Civitat. <hi>Killkenniae</hi> 
                     <date>12 die <hi>Auguſti, Anno. Dom.</hi> 1697.</date>
                  </dateline>
                  <signed>
                     <hi>John Pape,</hi> Com<hi rend="sup">r.</hi> for <hi>Killkenny.</hi>
                  </signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <div n="5" type="affidavit">
               <pb n="179" facs="tcp:60711:90"/>
               <head>N<hi rend="sup">o.</hi> V. <hi>Doctor</hi> Quail's <hi>Affidavit.</hi>
               </head>
               <p n="1">1. <hi>FRancis Quail,</hi> Doctor in Divinity, came this day before Me, and made Oath, that in the Year of our Lord 1675, he became Tutor to the Right Honourable <hi>Robert</hi> late Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> and continued as ſuch until the Death of <hi>John</hi> Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> Father of the ſaid Lord <hi>Robert;</hi> and after the Death of the ſaid <hi>John</hi> Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> the Tuition of the Right Honourable <hi>John,</hi> preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> was for ſome time committed to this Depo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nent, by Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> Baro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>net,
<pb n="180" facs="tcp:60711:91"/>
then Guardian and Uncle to the ſaid late Lord <hi>Robert</hi> and preſent Lord <hi>John;</hi> and this Deponent, by means thereof, hath been very converſant in that Honourable Family, and obſerv'd in the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> a great <hi>Care and Affection</hi> for the ſaid late Lord <hi>Robert,</hi> and preſent Lord <hi>John.</hi> And this Deponent further depoſeth, That he never obſerved, ſuſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted or diſcover'd any thing in the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert King</hi>'s ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nagement, during the time he the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert</hi> continued Guardian to the ſaid late Lord <hi>Robert,</hi> or preſent Lord <hi>John,</hi> but what was <hi>Juſt, Honeſt,</hi> and <hi>Honourable;</hi> and this Deponent always Believ'd the ſaid Sir <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert</hi>
                  <pb n="181" facs="tcp:60711:91"/>
to be ſincere and real in promoting the ſaid late Lord <hi>Robert,</hi> and preſent Lord <hi>John</hi>'s Intereſt and Advantage on all occaſions, not only in their Perſons, but in their Educati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, Fortunes, and Eſtates.</p>
               <p n="2">2. This Deponent further Depoſeth, That he never did enter into any <hi>Combination</hi> or <hi>Confederacy</hi> with <hi>Charles Goſling,</hi> Deceas'd, the Reverend <hi>Anthony Cope,</hi> Dean of <hi>Elphin, Anthony Raymond,</hi> Capt. <hi>Thomas Caulfield,</hi> or any of them, or any other Perſon or Perſons whatſoever, with intent or deſign to defeat or deprive the ſaid late Lord <hi>Robert,</hi> or preſent Lord <hi>John,</hi> of their or either of their Eſtates or Fortunes, or any part there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of;
<pb n="182" facs="tcp:60711:92"/>
and this Deponent doth not believe there was any <hi>Combina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion</hi> or <hi>Confederacy</hi> between the aforeſaid Perſons, or any of them, to any ſuch intent, or with any ſuch deſign.</p>
               <p n="3">3. This <hi>Deponent</hi> further de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſeth, That the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> did himſelf, from time to time, inſtruct the ſaid late Lord <hi>Robert</hi> in the knowledge of the <hi>Mathematicks,</hi> and was very ſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>licitous and careful in the ſaid late Lord <hi>Robert</hi>'s other Edu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cation and Learning.</p>
               <p n="4">4. This Deponent further depoſeth, That the ſaid Sir <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert King,</hi> being ſolicited by ſome Friends to permit the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Lord <hi>John</hi> to accompany the ſaid late Lord <hi>Robert</hi> in his
<pb n="183" facs="tcp:60711:92"/>
Travels, the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert</hi> re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fus'd to conſent thereto, ſaying, <hi>It was not fit to expoſe both the ſaid late Lord</hi> Robert, <hi>and pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Lord</hi> John <hi>together, to the hazards of the Seas, and foreign Countries.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="5">5. This Deponent further depoſeth, That, to the beſt of his remembrance, the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert King never did deſire him, this Deponent, to move the ſaid late Lord</hi> Robert <hi>to a Settlement of his Eſtate, in Excluſion of the preſent Lord</hi> John; but, on the contrary, this Deponent ſaith, <hi>That he the ſaid Sir</hi> Robert, <hi>ſhewed a great unwillingneſs to ſuch a Settlement when Propoſed to him;</hi> and the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> ſent this Deponent to the
<pb n="184" facs="tcp:60711:93"/>
ſaid late Lord <hi>Robert,</hi> to ſignifie his the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s <hi>diſlike of it, and to diſſwade him the ſaid Lord</hi> Robert <hi>from making thereof;</hi> which Meſſage this Deponent deliver'd to the ſaid late Lord <hi>Robert,</hi> to the beſt of this De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ponents remembrance, in a little Parlor at <hi>Boyle,</hi> at which the ſaid Lord <hi>Robert</hi> ſeem'd to be mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved, and ſaid, <hi>He would proceed in it,</hi> or words to that effect; <hi>and that</hi> Peggy Cahan<hi>'s Iſſue ſhould never enjoy his Eſtate.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="6">6. This Deponent further depoſeth, That he always ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerv<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>d a <hi>Backwardneſs</hi> in the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> touching ſuch a Settlement in Excluſion of the preſent Lord <hi>John</hi> and this deponent doth verily Believe
<pb n="185" facs="tcp:60711:93"/>
the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert</hi> never did, either by himſelf, or any other Perſon or Perſons whatſoever, perſwade or ſolicit the ſaid late Lord <hi>Robert,</hi> to make ſuch a Settlement; but, on the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary, this Deponent believeth ſuch <hi>Settlement was made by his the ſaid Lord</hi> Robert<hi>'s own meer Motion.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="7">7. This Deponent further depoſeth, That an Account came from Mr. <hi>Pach,</hi> then at <hi>Paris,</hi> that the preſent Lady <hi>Kingſton,</hi> (formerly a Servant in the Family) and her Couſin or Companion, were both with the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> then in <hi>Paris,</hi> and that he the ſaid Mr. <hi>Pach</hi> fear'd the <hi>conſequence;</hi> upon which this Deponent was
<pb n="186" facs="tcp:60711:94"/>
immediately ſent by the late Lord <hi>Robert</hi> and Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> to the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> to ſignifie their <hi>Reſentments,</hi> and to diſſwade his Lordſhip from the thoughts of the preſent Lady <hi>Kingſton;</hi> and accordingly this Deponent went with Letters and Propoſals (to the beſt of his Remembrance) of a <hi>Conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derable Advantage for the ſaid pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Lord</hi> Kingſton, <hi>and with great Promiſes, if he the ſaid pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Lord</hi> Kingſton <hi>obeyed, and Threatnings of being Diſinherited, if his Lordſhip would not be ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſed;</hi> all which this Deponent deliver'd to the ſaid preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> whoſe Anſwer was to this effect, <hi>viz.</hi> That he the ſaid preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>
                  <pb n="187" facs="tcp:60711:94"/>
had heard of this Deponent's coming, and his Buſineſs, and that his Lordſhip was very ſorry he had incurr'd his Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther's and Uncle's diſpleaſure, and to avoid it, his Lordſhip had ſent the Women (meaning the preſent Lady <hi>Kingſton</hi> and her ſaid Couſin) away, and did aſſure this deponent, with great and ſolemn Aſſeverations, that his Lordſhip would not con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cern himſelf with them any more; notwithſtanding which, the ſaid Mr. <hi>Pach</hi> and this De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ponent, ſometime afterwards, diſcover'd that the preſent Lady <hi>Kingſton</hi> and her ſaid Couſin, continued in <hi>Paris,</hi> and the ſaid preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> privately reſorted to them; upon which,
<pb n="188" facs="tcp:60711:95"/>
this Deponent and the ſaid Mr. <hi>Pach</hi> diſcover'd their Lodgings, and diſpers'd them; and this Deponent thereupon, at his next Meeting with the ſaid pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> taxed his Lordſhip with the unſincerity of his Profeſſions concerning the preſent Lady <hi>Kingſton,</hi> on which his Lordſhip ſeem'd to be much provok'd, and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clar'd, <hi>That his Paſſion was ſo great that he could not allay it;</hi> and drew a great part of his Sword out of the Scabbard, but this Deponent then telling his Lordſhip it was dangerous to draw a Sword there, being the Garden of the <hi>Palace Royal,</hi> his Lordſhip put it up again. This Deponent further depo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeth,
<pb n="189" facs="tcp:60711:95"/>
That meeting with the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> in <hi>Dublin,</hi> at his Return from <hi>Paris,</hi> this Deponent gave the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert</hi> an account of the afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid Tranſactions, upon which the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert ſeem'd to be,</hi> and this Deponent verily be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieves <hi>he was, much diſcompoſed and diſſatisfied.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="8">8. This Deponent further depoſeth, That the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> underſtanding that the ſaid late Lord <hi>Robert,</hi> while at <hi>Boyle,</hi> was likely to fall into company and familiarity of Perſons not ſuitable to his Lordſhip's Quality, he the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert,</hi> us'd his utmoſt en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deavours, as this Deponent verily believes, to divert his
<pb n="190" facs="tcp:60711:96"/>
Lordſhip from ſuch company; and the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert</hi> diſcoun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenanc'd them ſo far, that they ſeldom appear'd when the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert</hi> came to Viſit or Dine with the ſaid Lord <hi>Robert.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="9">9. This Deponent further depoſeth, That the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> was very <hi>Solicitous, Induſtrious, and Active to have the ſaid late Lord</hi> Robert <hi>well Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried;</hi> and to that purpoſe, he the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert,</hi> propoſed ſeveral conſiderable Matches to his Lordſhip, <hi>viz.</hi> The Lady <hi>Elizabeth Cheſterfield,</hi> and Lady <hi>Elizabeth Cromwell;</hi> and in pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecution of a Match with the ſaid Lady <hi>Elizabeth Cromwell,</hi> a conſiderable Progreſs was made, and was ſo near a con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cluſion,
<pb n="191" facs="tcp:60711:96"/>
that this Deponent was inform'd, and believes <hi>the Wed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding Ring was bought.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="10">10. This Deponent further depoſeth, That the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> as this Deponent does verily believe, did, as much as in him lay, <hi>endeavour to prevent the diſhonourable Amour, and unfortunate Marriage of the preſent Lord with the preſent Lady</hi> Kingſton; and this De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ponent hath been credibly in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>form'd, and believeth the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert King propoſed a con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiderable Portion to the preſent Lady</hi> Kingſton, (then a Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vant) <hi>in order to have her Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried to another Servant then in the Family, on purpoſe, and with deſign, to prevent the preſent</hi>
                  <pb n="192" facs="tcp:60711:97"/>
                  <hi>Lord</hi> Kingſton<hi>'s being inveigled, and to ſecure his Lordſhip from danger.</hi>
               </p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>Fr. Quail.</signed>
                  <dateline>
                     <hi>Jurat coram me</hi> 
                     <date>16 <hi>die</hi> Februarii, 1698.</date>
                  </dateline>
                  <signed>John Usſher.</signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <div n="6" type="case">
               <head>
                  <hi>N<hi rend="sup">o.</hi> VI. The Caſe of Mr.</hi> John King, <hi>only Brother of the preſent Lord</hi> Kingſton <hi>of</hi> Ireland.</head>
               <head type="sub">Humbly offer'd to His Majeſty's moſt Gracious Conſideration.</head>
               <p>THE ſaid Mr. <hi>King,</hi> when very Young, fell in Love with a Gentlewoman, much about
<pb n="193" facs="tcp:60711:97"/>
his own Age, and, after <hi>many Hardſhips and Difficulties ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fered on that account,</hi> Married her at his Age of Eighteen.</p>
               <p>And tho her Virtue and un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtain'd Reputation exempted her from all Calumnies, yet her being a Native <hi>Iriſh</hi> Woman, and her wanting a Fortune, was ſuggeſted by Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> his Uncle, a juſt Cauſe of deſerving his ſaid Brother's Anger and Diſpleaſure.</p>
               <p>Upon this Foundation the ſaid Uncle built his whole Deſigns, and magnifying every little Circumſtance into a Crime, and pretending that the Honour of the Family ſhould be irreparably loſt, in Caſe any of the ſaid Mr. <hi>King's</hi> Iſſue, by his ſaid Wife, ſhould be ſuffer'd to Inherit.</p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="194" facs="tcp:60711:98"/>
He at laſt prevail'd with the ſaid Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> to ſettle his Eſtate, upon his Dying without Iſſue, upon him and his Heirs, in ſuch manner, that the ſaid Mr. <hi>King,</hi> and his Heirs, ſhould be wholly Excluded from the Poſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bility of ever Enjoying the ſaid Eſtate, tho' in truth, moſt of it deſcended from the ſaid Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> and Mr. <hi>King</hi>'s Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, as Heir at Law to the Family of <hi>Fitzgeralds,</hi> formerly called the <hi>White-Knight:</hi> But the Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> as Mr. <hi>King</hi> is in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>form'd, reſerv'd to himſelf a Power of Altering the ſaid Settlement at any time within a Year.</p>
               <p>Now foraſmuch as the Honour and Title muſt deſcend to Mr. <hi>King,</hi> or his Heirs, upon his Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther's
<pb n="195" facs="tcp:60711:98"/>
Dying without Iſſue, and that if no Eſtate be left to ſupport the ſame, it may become chargeable to the Crown, whoſe Glory as well as Intereſt it is, to reſcue the No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bility from Beggery and Contempt, the ſaid Mr. <hi>King</hi> doth throw him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf at His Majeſty's Feet for His Royal Protection, moſt Humbly beſeeching Him, that He would be graciouſly pleaſed to ſend for the ſaid Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> who is now in Town, and to intimate His Royal Pleaſure to him, of having the Eſtate ſo ſettled, as the ſaid Mr. <hi>King,</hi> and his Heirs, may not be excluded from Enjoying the ſame upon the ſaid Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Dying with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out Iſſue; whereunto (as Mr. <hi>King</hi> verily believes) the ſaid Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> will readily agree,
<pb n="196" facs="tcp:60711:99"/>
being in his own Nature ſo kind, juſt, and generous, that he will be glad to have a fair Opportunity of avoiding what the Importunity of the ſaid Uncle in ſome meaſure forc'd from him.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="7" type="case">
               <head>N<hi rend="sup">o.</hi> VII. Mr. <hi>John King</hi>'s Caſe, humbly Offered to the Conſidera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the High Court of Parliament.</head>
               <head type="sub">This Caſe having been ſome time ago Printed at large, it will be ſuffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cient at this time to Re-Print the following Extract out of it.</head>
               <p>AND ſince Love either finds or makes all Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple equal, the Conſideration of the Diſparity of her <hi>(the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent</hi>
                  <pb n="197" facs="tcp:60711:99"/>
                  <hi>Lady</hi> Kingſton<hi>'s)</hi> Fortune could give no check to his Affection; and therefore grow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing up with his Years, <hi>after many Hardſhips and Difficulties ſuffered by them both on that ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count,</hi> it produc'd a Marriage about his Age of Eighteen.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="8" type="letter">
               <head>N<hi rend="sup">o.</hi> VIII. <hi>The Subſtance of Mr.</hi> Raymond<hi>'s Letter to Sir</hi> Robert King, <hi>as it is ſet down in the</hi> Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terials for a Bill of Diſcovery againſt Sir <hi>Robert King, &amp;c.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>THE next thing I have to acquaint you with is, That my Lord did, a Day or
<pb n="198" facs="tcp:60711:100"/>
two before he went out of Town, perfect a Deed of Set<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlement, which Captain <hi>Choppine</hi> prepar'd, of which I had no certain Notice until his Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip was gone, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> upon which I waited upon Captain <hi>Chop<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pine,</hi> who ſhew'd me the Deed, which to me is one of the ſtrangeſt I ever ſaw, and ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mire at it, conſidering I often heard you ſay, <hi>That it was very reaſonable my Lord ſhould have power, and a power only in himſelf, to alter the Uſes as he ſaw cauſe;</hi> for which reaſon there ought to be ſuch a Clauſe inſerted, which is not, nor Proviſion for younger Children. I diſcours'd Captain <hi>Choppine,</hi> who is for poſting on a Fine and Reco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very,
<pb n="199" facs="tcp:60711:100"/>
for Confirmation of it, with all ſpeed, and told him, that ſince his Lordſhip was juſt on Marrying, or Expectation of it, it had been better let alone at preſent Levying the Fine, which muſt render it publick, and contract great Charge and talk, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> I have written back hence to Captain <hi>Choppine,</hi> and begged him to ſuſpend the Fine until he heard from you; he conſiders but one thing, and my Zeal for the ſame is as great as his, but would have it done with other Conſiderations, which, I am ſure, are ſuch as will be ſatis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>factory to you, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> for I be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve he has not taken your Meaſures right, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="9" type="letter">
               <pb n="200" facs="tcp:60711:101"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>N<hi rend="sup">o.</hi> IX. The preſent Lord</hi> Kingſton<hi>'s Letter to Mr.</hi> Goſling.</head>
               <opener>
                  <salute>SIR,</salute>
               </opener>
               <p>
                  <hi>I</hi> Thought that all my Civilities would have obliged you, when my Couſin told you I was Married to ſuch a one, you would have per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſudded her that I had a little more Wit than ſo; but ſhe is apt to be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve all Ill of me; <hi>let me damn my ſelf to the Pit of Hell, I muſt never be believed, but</hi> Bridget <hi>and</hi> Will<hi>'s Words muſt go before my Oaths.</hi> Have I ſtrove to ſerve her with all I have in this World, nay, I would not have ſpar'd my Heart's Blood
<pb n="201" facs="tcp:60711:101"/>
to have done her good, and is this my Reward? <hi>Would that be the Effects of one who was counted Wiſe, to play the Fool to go Marry a Scullian, tho' he lov'd her ever ſo well?</hi> I may as well ſay ſhe will Marry crook'd <hi>Will,</hi> as what ſhe thinks of me. Except ſhe and you ſend me ſome <hi>Recompence for the Injury you have done me, by your unworthy and dirty Thoughts, I'll never forgive you,</hi> and do not let it come about by Mr. <hi>Pach</hi> any more. Of Two ſo Wiſe as my Couſin and you, I never ſaw Sir <hi>Martin</hi> act a more ſilly part; read her Letter, wherein I frighten her, but it is for nothing elſe, for I love her ſtill, as well as ever, and that ſhe ſhall ſee at laſt. Read her
<pb n="202" facs="tcp:60711:102"/>
Letters pray, and promiſe you love GOD and Me. Shew this to no body but Couſin <hi>Sue,</hi> and let her burn hers.</p>
               <closer>
                  <dateline>
                     <hi>PARIS,</hi> 
                     <date>May 23.</date>
                  </dateline>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <div n="10" type="letter">
               <head>
                  <hi>N<hi rend="sup">o.</hi> X. Doctor</hi> Horneck<hi>'s Letter to Sir</hi> Robert King.</head>
               <opener>
                  <salute>SIR,</salute>
               </opener>
               <p>
                  <hi>I</hi> Had yours, and am heartily glad my old Friend and Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quaintance is Alive and well. I have been indiſpos'd with the Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtemper of the <hi>Stone</hi> and <hi>Bloody-Water</hi> theſe Six Weeks; Bleſſed be GOD, there appear ſome ſigns of Recovery. Concerning your
<pb n="203" facs="tcp:60711:102"/>
Nephew, the Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> I have almoſt forgot Particulars of ſo long ſtanding, or done ſo many Years ago, yet I do remember, <hi>he own'd he gave his Conſent to the paſſing of the Eſtate to you,</hi> only, as is uſual in ſuch Caſes, pleaded Youth and Fear, or ſome ſuch Argument. There is a Young-Man, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>I am, Sir, Your Affectionate Friend, And Humble Servant, A. Horneck.</signed>
                  <dateline>
                     <date>Sept. 22.</date>
                  </dateline>
               </closer>
               <trailer>
                  <hi>For the Right Honourable Sir</hi> Robert King, <hi>Kt. one of His Majeſty's moſt Honble. Privy-Council in the Kingdom of</hi> Ire<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land, <hi>at</hi> Dublin.</trailer>
            </div>
            <div n="11" type="instructions">
               <pb n="204" facs="tcp:60711:103"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>N<hi rend="sup">o.</hi> XI.</hi> The late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Paper, Written with his own Hand, containing Directions for draw<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing up his Lordſhip's Anſwer to Mr. <hi>King</hi>'s Caſe.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>THat Mr.</hi> King <hi>fell in Love, I believe to be true; but that his Wife is a Gentlewoman, is as falſe as any falſe</hi> Suppoſition <hi>can be:</hi> Her firſt Riſe was to be my Poultry-Woman's Servant, and her greateſt to be my Dairy-Maid, till ſhe became his Spouſe: That it was upon this occaſion I Settled my Eſtate from Him and Hers, into a Family of good Extraction, and not (as he moſt unjuſtly ſays)
<pb n="205" facs="tcp:60711:103"/>
by the advice and deſire of Sir <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert King</hi> my Uncle, who was the only Man (of all thoſe that knew my Deſigns) that Oppos'd ſo juſt a Settlement, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="12" type="letter">
               <head>
                  <hi>N<hi rend="sup">o.</hi> XII. The preſent Lord</hi> Kingſton<hi>'s Letter to Sir</hi> Robert King.</head>
               <opener>
                  <salute>Dear Uncle,</salute>
               </opener>
               <p>IT is not for want either of Duty or Reſpect, that I have not waited upon you ſince my coming for <hi>England,</hi> but becauſe I know the Sight of ſo unpleaſing an Ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ject cannot be grateful to ſo near a Relation as you are; Therefore I thought it better to live both pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vate
<pb n="206" facs="tcp:60711:104"/>
and retir'd from the ſight of all my Relations and Friends, than to give them a Subject to Diſcourſe of, which the Sight of me cannot continually chooſe but do: I hope you will not take it ill, ſeeing I have given you a true account of the Reaſon: By this I ſhall ſoon be forgotten by you all, and ſhall en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joy quiet of Mind, by delivering my ſelf from the bitter Reproaches due to me from ſo good Relations; and tho' perhaps you may never ſee me, yet as far as my power ſhall ever reach, you ſhall ever find me</p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>Your Dutiful and Obedient Nephew
Jo. King.</signed>
               </closer>
               <trailer>
                  <hi>To the Honourable Sir</hi> Robert King.</trailer>
            </div>
            <div n="13" type="deposition">
               <pb n="207" facs="tcp:60711:104"/>
               <head>N<hi rend="sup">o.</hi> XIII. <hi>The Depoſition of</hi> William Conolly <hi>
                     <abbr>Esq</abbr>
                  </hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <hi>WIlliam Conolly,</hi> of the City of <hi>Dublin,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Esq</abbr> Depoſeth, That having ſome earneſt oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caſions with <hi>Robert</hi> Lord Baron of <hi>Kingſton</hi> Deceas'd, he re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paired to <hi>Boyle</hi> about the fourth of <hi>October</hi> 1693, and ſtayed with the ſaid Lord for ſeveral days, in which <hi>time,</hi> and at <hi>ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral times</hi> before, he heard the ſaid Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> expreſs him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf with great diſſatisfaction and diſlike of the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> and the diſhonour he had placed upon the Family;
<pb n="208" facs="tcp:60711:105"/>
and often ſaid, <hi>That he ſhould never Enjoy any part of his Eſtate,</hi> and hoped his Uncle, Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> would be juſt to him in his Intentions in that Matter, tho' he expected much more from his Son, meaning <hi>John King</hi> 
                  <abbr>Esq</abbr> to whom the ſaid L<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 
                  <hi>Robert</hi> ſaid his Eſtate would come. This Deponent further depoſeth, That the ſaid <hi>Robert</hi> Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> ſaid, and expreſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed himſelf with concern, fear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing that the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> might be too eaſie pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vail'd upon by the now Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> or words to that pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe.</p>
               <p>The Cauſe of this Depo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nent's Diſcourſe and Know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge is, that he was intimate
<pb n="209" facs="tcp:60711:105"/>
with the ſaid <hi>Robert</hi> Lord <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton,</hi> and was concern'd for him as his Agent and So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>licitor.</p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>Will. Conolly,</signed>
                  <dateline>
                     <hi>Jurat coram me</hi> 
                     <date>23 Decemb. 1698.</date>
                  </dateline>
                  <signed>J. Coghill.</signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <div n="14" type="deposition">
               <head>N<hi rend="sup">o.</hi> XIV. <hi>The Depoſition of</hi> Nola Mur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phey, <hi>taken before the Reve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rend Dean</hi> Anthony Cope, <hi>One of His Majeſty's Juſtices of the Peace for the County of</hi> Roſcommon.</head>
               <p>THE Examinate being duly Sworn on the Holy Evangeliſts, depoſeth, That being a Servant with Sir <hi>Robert</hi>
                  <pb n="210" facs="tcp:60711:106"/>
                  <hi>King,</hi> his Lady, and her Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, for above Forty Years, was intruſted by him, as his Houſe-keeper, with ſeveral Goods and Papers, on his go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing for <hi>England,</hi> before the late Troubles; moſt of which ſhe, the Deponent, diſpers'd a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt ſuch of the <hi>Iriſh</hi> as ſhe thought would keep them ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſt, and give them back again; and tho' in the Troubles ſome <hi>Iriſh</hi> Officers and Soldiers came to her Maſter's Houſe, where ſhe was left, and threatned to ſend her to Goal if ſhe did not tell where ſhe had the ſaid Goods; yet ſhe would not tell them, let them ſay what they would. But this preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> coming to the Houſe,
<pb n="211" facs="tcp:60711:106"/>
with ſeveral in his Company, he, ſoon after his being in it, took the Deponent from this Company, and went with her into the Room call'd the <hi>Nur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſery,</hi> where he enquir'd very privately when ſhe heard from his Uncle and Aunt, and the Children, and ſpake ſo very tenderly of them, uſing often the word, <hi>his dear Uncle and Aunt, and dear Couſins,</hi> that ſhe could have truſted him with all the Things and Papers ſhe had in the World of her Maſter's, and did believe his Lordſhip ſpake from his Heart, becauſe of his being long and often in her Maſter's Houſe, and ſhe ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerv'd what great Kindneſs and tender Care her Maſter and
<pb n="212" facs="tcp:60711:107"/>
Lady had of his Lordſhip, as if he were their own Child; and after all his kind Words, his Lordſhip ſaid, <hi>Nola, what you have of my Uncle's, let me know; for if he had a Thouſand Pounds worth, I would not take a Penny worth of them for my ſelf, but keep it for him, fearing others ſhould take it from him; but be ſure you ſhew me every thing of his that you have; let the World go as it will, I hope they will not loſe their own.</hi> And when he was leaving this De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ponent, his Lordſhip ſaid, <hi>Nola, If what I have ſaid to you were heard, or known, this would be cut off,</hi> (drawing his Fingers croſs his Neck;) by which, the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ponent thinks, he meant that
<pb n="213" facs="tcp:60711:107"/>
his Head would be cut off: By theſe, and other fair words, ſhe, the Deponent, went next day to <hi>Boyle,</hi> and ſhew'd him ſome Things, and all the Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pers which were her Maſter's; and when his Lordſhip came to the Box of Papers, he be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gan to read them, the Deponent upon this was very much trou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled, and to get them out of his Lordſhip's Hands, told it was late, and ſhe muſt go home; he bad her go home, for that he would take as much Care of the Papers as ſhe could, and would put them up when he had done with them. She went home to <hi>Rockingham,</hi> and next day went to <hi>Boyle,</hi> to look after the Papers, and found
<pb n="214" facs="tcp:60711:108"/>
ſome in the Box, and ſome on the Floor; but ſhe miſt ſome of the Papers, and a Leathern Bag, in which ſhe believes his Lordſhip put the Papers he took away; for ſhe ſaw there was not near ſo many as ſhe ſhew'd his Lordſhip the day before.</p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>
                     <hi>Nola</hi> 8 <hi>Murphey,</hi> her Mark.</signed>
                  <dateline>
                     <hi>Jurat coram me</hi> 
                     <date>Octob. 19. 1697.</date>
                  </dateline>
                  <signed>Ant. Cope.</signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <div n="15" type="deposition">
               <pb n="215" facs="tcp:60711:108"/>
               <head>N<hi rend="sup">o.</hi> XV. <hi>Mr.</hi> Raymond<hi>'s Second Depoſition.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <hi>ANthony Raymond</hi> of <hi>Gar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rane,</hi> in the County of <hi>Cork,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Esq</abbr> came before Me this day, and made Oath, That a little before the Right Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nourable <hi>Robert</hi> Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> was Married, the ſaid Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> imployed this Depo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nent to get a Deed of Settle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment drawn, in order to his Marriage, which Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> Baronet, underſtanding, he, the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert,</hi> deſir'd this Deponent to acquaint his Lordſhip, that by the former
<pb n="216" facs="tcp:60711:109"/>
Deed of Settlement that he had made, the Eſtate was, for want of Iſſue of his own Body, to go to Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> and his Sons; in which Deed there was a Power, or Proviſo, that if the ſaid Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> ſhould Marry, it ſhould be in his Power, ſome Months before and after his Marriage, to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>voke the ſaid Deed, and to make ſuch new Settlement, and limit Remainders or Uſes, as he ſhould think fit, by which it was then in his Power to ſettle the Reverſion of his Eſtate, for want of his own Iſſue, on his Brother, and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore deſir'd his Lordſhip would ſeriouſly conſider, whether he was not bound in Conſcience
<pb n="217" facs="tcp:60711:109"/>
to ſettle it on his Brother, and that he ſhould conſult ſome of the Eminent Divines in the City, meaning <hi>London,</hi> whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther he was not oblig'd in Conſcience to ſettle it on his Brother, whilſt it was in his Power; for that if a new Deed and Settlement were made on his Marriage, with the like Uſes and Limitations as the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther was, it would not be in his Power afterwards to alter it, or to that or the like effect; which Meſſage this Deponent did faithfully deliver unto the ſaid Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> who bad this Deponent to tell his Uncle, meaning Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> that he deſir<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>d him not to give him any more Trouble about it,
<pb n="218" facs="tcp:60711:110"/>
for that he was reſolv'd to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinue the Settlement as it was, and that if his Uncle would not accept of it, he would ſettle it on his Sons, or to that or the like purpoſe: Which Anſwer this Deponent did de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liver unto the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> whereupon (as this De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ponent believeth) the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> did acquieſce.</p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>Ant. Raymond.</signed>
                  <dateline>Jurat apud <hi>Limerick</hi> 
                     <date>2<hi>do</hi> die <hi>Auguſti,</hi> 1697. coram me.</date>
                  </dateline>
                  <signed>Robert Smith, Un. Magiſtr. extraor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>din. in Cancell. <hi>Hi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berniae.</hi>
                  </signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <div n="16" type="deposition">
               <pb n="219" facs="tcp:60711:110"/>
               <head>N<hi rend="sup">o.</hi> XVI. <hi>The Depoſition of</hi> William Teams.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>WIlliam Teams</hi> came volun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tary before us, and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſed on the Holy Evangeliſts, <hi>Imprimis,</hi> That he being Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vant to the late Lord <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton,</hi> was very well acquainted with <hi>Margaret Cahan,</hi> when ſhe lived with <hi>Katherine Nolan,</hi> Hen-Woman to the ſaid Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> and afterwards when the ſaid <hi>Margaret</hi> was Servant to Mrs. <hi>Suſanna Horſey:</hi> And this Deponent ſaith, That it was commonly reported, that the now Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> and
<pb n="220" facs="tcp:60711:111"/>
the ſaid <hi>Margaret</hi> were too familiar and great, and that when Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> heard thereof, he prevail'd with his Nephew, the late Lord <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton,</hi> to promiſe this Deponent <hi>Fifty Pounds,</hi> to Marry the ſaid <hi>Margaret Cahan,</hi> purpoſely that ſhe might be removed from the now Lord <hi>Kingſton;</hi> but this taking no effect, the ſaid Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> gave or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders to diſcharge her from Serving in the Family any lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger; which accordingly was done.</p>
               <p>2. The Deponent further ſaith, That tho' he lived all the time in the ſame Family with the ſaid <hi>Margaret Cahan,</hi> yet he never heard that the
<pb n="221" facs="tcp:60711:111"/>
now Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> deſign'd to make her his Wife, until he heard that ſhe follow'd him into <hi>France.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>3. The Deponent further ſaith, That the now Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi> was much troubled and concern'd when the ſaid <hi>Margaret Cahan</hi> was diſcharg'd out of the Family.</p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>
                     <hi>Will.</hi> 
                     <g ref="char:cross">✚</g> 
                     <hi>Teams.</hi>
                  </signed>
                  <dateline>
                     <hi>The above Depoſiti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons were volun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tarily Sworn, and Signed before us,</hi> 
                     <date> this <hi>Seventh of</hi> Decemb. 1698.</date>
                  </dateline>
                  <signed>Ant. Cope.</signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <div n="17" type="deposition">
               <pb n="222" facs="tcp:60711:112"/>
               <head>N<hi rend="sup">o.</hi> XVII. <hi>The Depoſition of</hi> John Dingwell.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>JOhn Dingwell</hi> came volunta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rily before Us, and Depo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed on the Holy Evangeliſts,</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Imprimis,</hi> That the late Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s Exceſs in Company-keeping was a great grief and trouble to Sir <hi>Robert</hi> his Uncle: And this Deponent ſaith, That when thoſe Perſons who uſual<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly frequented with the ſaid Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> heard of Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s coming to Viſit or Dine with his Nephew, the ſaid Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> they con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtantly ſhun'd the ſaid Sir <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert King,</hi> and would not be ſeen by him.</p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="223" facs="tcp:60711:112"/>
2. The Deponent further ſaith, That as ſoon as Sir <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert King</hi> heard that his Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phew, the now Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> and <hi>Margaret Cahan,</hi> were too Great and Familiar, he caus'd the ſaid <hi>Margaret</hi> to be turn'd out of her Service, and ſaid, that if ever afterwards he heard of her being in <hi>Boyle,</hi> that he would cauſe her to be ſeverely Puniſh'd.</p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>John Dingwell.</signed>
                  <dateline>The above <hi>Depoſitions</hi> were voluntarily Sworn and Sign'd before Us, <date>this <hi>7th</hi> of <hi>Decemb.</hi> 1698.</date>
                  </dateline>
                  <signed>
                     <list>
                        <item>Andrew Blackburn.</item>
                        <item>Anthony Cope.</item>
                        <item>Gilbert King.</item>
                     </list>
                  </signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <div n="18" type="deposition">
               <pb n="224" facs="tcp:60711:113"/>
               <head>N<hi rend="sup">o.</hi> XVIII. <hi>The Depoſition of Mrs.</hi> Mary Choppine.</head>
               <p>THe ſaid <hi>Mary Choppine,</hi> came this day before Me, and made Oath, That her on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Daughter being Married to Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> ſhe this Depo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nent was often with them at <hi>Boyle</hi> and <hi>Rockingham,</hi> and took notice of the great Care and Kindneſs Sir <hi>Robert</hi> had for both his Nephews, but more particularly for the preſent Lord <hi>Kingſton,</hi> for whom Sir <hi>Robert</hi> ſeem'd to have a more tender Affection, which this Deponent believes he had, till his Brother, the late Lord, was
<pb n="225" facs="tcp:60711:113"/>
gone to Travel; and that her Son, Sir <hi>Robert,</hi> had heard of the preſent Lord's being too kind and familiar with a Girl, called <hi>Peggy Cahan,</hi> an under Servant in his Brother's Houſe. This Deponent further Depoſeth, That on Sir <hi>Robert</hi>'s hearing of it, he (as this Deponent was credibly inform'd) ſent to Mrs. <hi>Horſey,</hi> the Houſe-keeper, who was a Kinſwoman of the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Lord's, by the Mothers ſide, to have the ſaid Girl turn'd out of her Service; but the preſent Lord procur'd her ſtay, as this Deponent verily believes, and has heard from thoſe his Lordſhip employed about it. This Deponent further depo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeth, That ſhe did not at that
<pb n="226" facs="tcp:60711:114"/>
time hear, nor did ſhe in the leaſt think, or believe, that the preſent Lord had any deſign of making <hi>Margaret Cahan,</hi> or any ſuch Perſon, his Wife. And this Deponent further depoſeth, That when the late Lord <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton</hi> heard that the ſaid <hi>Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>garet Cahan</hi> was with his Brother in <hi>France,</hi> he was ſo much of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fended, that he reſolved to diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>inherit him, and ſettle the E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtate on his Uncle, Sir <hi>Robert King:</hi> But this Deponent found Sir <hi>Robert</hi> againſt it, and knows, that he often refus'd to accept of the Settlement his Lordſhip intended to make on him; at which this Deponent was diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pleaſed, and ſpoke to Sir <hi>Robert</hi> about it, and often heard her
<pb n="227" facs="tcp:60711:114"/>
Husband ſay, that Sir <hi>Robert</hi> was Mad to refuſe an Eſtate ſo offer'd: And the late Lord ſaid, if his Uncle would not accept of his Eſtate, he would give it to another; nay, to any one, rather than his Brother, as this Deponent has been often told. And this Deponent fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther depoſeth, That ſhe be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieves Sir <hi>Robert King</hi> did not accept of the Settlement of the late Lord's Eſtate until he had the Opinions of ſome of the beſt Divines in <hi>England,</hi> that it was lawful for him to accept thereof.</p>
               <closer>
                  <dateline>
                     <hi>Jurat coram me</hi> 
                     <date>11 <hi>die</hi> Maii, <hi>Anno Dom.</hi> 1699.</date>
                  </dateline>
                  <signed>John Usſher.</signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <div n="19" type="affidavit">
               <pb n="228" facs="tcp:60711:115"/>
               <head>N<hi rend="sup">o.</hi> XIX. <hi>The Affidavit of</hi> Thomas Yeeden, <hi>Clerk.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>I <hi>Thomas Yeeden,</hi> do know that <hi>Charles Holcroft,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Esq</abbr> had a conſiderable Eſtate in the County of <hi>Golloway,</hi> near, and in <hi>Tuam:</hi> That he ſold the ſame ſeveral Years before the War of Eighty Eight; ſome part to my ſelf, of which he Levied a Fine, and com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Recovery; ſome unto <hi>Thomas Dean</hi> of <hi>Golloway,</hi> Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chant; ſome unto <hi>Nicholas Bermingham</hi> near <hi>Barnedarrick;</hi> ſome unto <hi>James Johnſton,</hi> Clerk; ſome unto <hi>Edmund</hi>
                  <pb n="229" facs="tcp:60711:115"/>
                  <hi>Kelly</hi> of <hi>Fiddane,</hi> in the ſame County: That ſome of theſe ſaid Perſons underſtanding that the ſaid <hi>Charles Holcroft</hi> made a prior Deed of his E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtate unto the Right Honou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable <hi>John</hi> Lord <hi>Kingſton</hi>'s ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond Son, the now Right Honourable <hi>John</hi> Lord <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton,</hi> did commence a Suit in His Majeſty's High Court of <hi>Chancery</hi> in <hi>Ireland,</hi> againſt Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> Baronet, praying the Deed to be brought into Court, which, as I was told, was produc'd, and what the Iſſue of thoſe Proceedings were, referr to the Rules then ſet down. I have heard that the Deed was faulty. The Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nagement of that Suit againſt
<pb n="230" facs="tcp:60711:116"/>
Sir <hi>Robert</hi> was left to Mr. <hi>Ed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mund Renell.</hi> I heard that <hi>Charles Holcroft,</hi> aforeſaid, had ſome Lands in <hi>Leiceſter,</hi> which he diſpos'd of to <hi>Robert Choppine,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Esq</abbr> Deceaſed, which, I have heard, was ſet for <hi>Eighty Pounds</hi> ſterl. a Year, and no more. All which I hereby Certifie and Depoſe.</p>
               <closer>
                  <dateline>Witneſs my Hand <date>this <hi>Fifth</hi> of <hi>October,</hi> 1698.</date>
                  </dateline>
                  <signed>Thomas Yeeden.</signed>
                  <dateline>Sworn before me <date>the Day and Year a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid.</date>
                  </dateline>
                  <signed>Anth. Cope.</signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <div n="20" type="letter">
               <pb n="231" facs="tcp:60711:116"/>
               <head>N<hi rend="sup">o.</hi> XX. <hi>An Extract out of</hi> Robert <hi>late Lord</hi> Kingſton<hi>'s Letter to Sir</hi> Robert King, <hi>dated</hi> June <hi>the 29th,</hi> 1688.</head>
               <opener>
                  <salute>Deareſt Uncle,</salute>
               </opener>
               <p>I Know my Brother's Aim is Poſſeſſion, believing I may miſcarry through the great Love our Country-Men have for me; but if I could more firmly ſettle what I have, I would, and rivet it, rather than it ſhould be ever alter'd.</p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>I am ſtill, <hi>Deareſt <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>NCLE,</hi> Your moſt Obedient and Moſt Humble Servant.</signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <div n="21" type="account">
               <pb n="232" facs="tcp:60711:117"/>
               <head>N<hi rend="sup">o.</hi> XXI. <hi>An Account ſtated under the Hand and Seal of Mr.</hi> John King, <hi>(the preſent Lord</hi> Kingſton.)</head>
               <p>WHereas upon Ballance of Accounts with my Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther the Right Honourable <hi>Robert</hi> Lord Baron of <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton,</hi> as my Guardian, it ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pears, that I owe unto my ſaid Brother the Summ of <hi>One Hundred Ninety Five Pounds Eighteen Shillings</hi> and <hi>Six Pence Three Farthings.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>And whereas upon Ballance of Accounts with my Uncle, Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> Baronet, it appears, that my ſaid Uncle
<pb n="233" facs="tcp:60711:117"/>
owes me the Summ of <hi>One Hundred Thirty Four Pounds Two Shillings</hi> and a <hi>Half Peny;</hi> I do, for the Satisfying unto my ſaid Brother the aforeſaid Sum of 195 <hi>l.</hi> 18 <hi>s.</hi> 6 <hi>d.</hi> ¾. hereby Aſſign, and make over unto my ſaid Brother, his Executors, Adminiſtrators, and Aſſigns, the ſaid Summ of 134 <hi>l.</hi> 2 <hi>s.</hi> 0 <hi>d.</hi> ½. due unto me from my ſaid Uncle, and to give Diſcharge or Diſcharges unto him my ſaid Uncle for the ſame, which ſhall be as effectual to all Intents and Purpoſes as if the ſame was, or were actually given by my ſelf. And I do promiſe, co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venant, and undertake to pay unto my ſaid Brother, his Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ecutors,
<pb n="234" facs="tcp:60711:118"/>
Adminiſtrators, or Aſſigns, upon, or before, the <hi>Firſt</hi> Day of <hi>May</hi> next, the Summ of <hi>Sixty One Pounds Sixteen Shillings</hi> and <hi>Six Pence Farthing,</hi> to compleat the ſaid Sum of 195 <hi>l.</hi> 18<hi>s.</hi> 6<hi>d.</hi> ¾. ſo due to my ſaid Brother. In Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs whereof I have hereunto ſet my Hand and Seal this <hi>Sixth</hi> Day of <hi>February,</hi> 1683.</p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>
                     <hi>John King.</hi> 
                     <g ref="char:cross">✚</g>
                  </signed>
                  <signed>
                     <list>
                        <head>Being preſent</head>
                        <item>Ant. Raymond.</item>
                        <item>Fr. Quail.</item>
                        <item>Hen. Faell.</item>
                     </list>
                  </signed>
               </closer>
               <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
               <pb facs="tcp:60711:118"/>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
